(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
オープン！
Open!
わぁ～！
Yay!
ということで本日は…
So, today...
はい。
Yes.
あずいろ食堂、開店！
Azuiro Cafeteria, Open!
わぁ～！
Yay!
そして…
And...
昨日ね、あずいろで仕込みをしたんですけれども…
Azuiro did the prep yesterday, but...
やりました。
We did.
今日はFUWAMOCOちゃんにも来ていただいて…
Today we have FUWAMOCO here...
お給仕をしていただきます。
to help us serve.
YA～！お給仕します！
BAU BAU! We'll serve!
開店、開店。
Open, open.
ということで…
So...
ちょっと早速…
Uh, immediately...
ちょっとあの、事件が発生してましてですね…
Um, a bit of an incident has occurred...
開店前から並んでるお客さんが数名いらっしゃる…
There are a few customers who have been lining up since before opening...
もういるんですよね。
They are already here.
じゃあの、お尻がない組から…お尻？
So, from the group with no butts... butts?
あの、時間の…時間があんまない組から…
Um, time... from the group that doesn't have much time...
OK, OK.
言い方…
Phrasing...
お尻…お尻…
Butts... butts...
言い方が…
The phrasing is...
「お尻がない」って言うじゃん。
You say "no butts" [time at the end], right?
言いますよね！？
People say that, right!?
じゃ…よかったら、じゃあ…
Well... if you'd like, then...
どっちからします？
Which one should we start with?
First Customer!
誰かな？
Who is it?
もう声入ってますよ。
Our voices are already on.
自己紹介からですね。
Start with self-introductions.
じゃ、いる人からね。
Start with who's here.
あ、獅白ぼたんでーす。
Ah, I'm Shishiro Botan.
ししろん先輩！
Shishiron-senpai!
はい、角巻わためでーす。
Yes, I'm Tsunomaki Watame.
ジンギスカンでーす。
I'm Genghis Khan [Lamb].
ジンギスカン！？
Genghis Khan!?
そして、まつりです。
And, I'm Matsuri.
神！
God!
神！？
God!?
今日の第一お客様として…
As today's first customers...
開店前から並んでいただいて。
You've been lining up since before opening.
10分前ぐらいから並んでた。
Lined up since about 10 mins ago.
「まつり先輩向かってる」ってコメントを見て…
I saw a comment saying "Matsuri-senpai is heading there"...
「あれ？後ろにいるじゃん」って…
"Huh? She's behind us"...
びっくりしました。
I was surprised.
ということで…
So...
今日はですね、画面見てる皆さん、こちらに…
Today, for everyone watching the screen, over here...
お品書きがあるんですけど…
We have the menu...
手は風真いろはです。
The hand is Kazama Iroha.
上から読み上げますね。
I'll read from the top.
おでんが…大根、卵、こんにゃく…
Oden... Daikon, Egg, Konjac...
ちくわ、昆布、さつま揚げ…
Chikuwa, Kelp, Fried Fish Cake...
はんぺん、餅巾着、牛すじ。
Hanpen, Mochi Pouch, Beef Tendon.
で、あとウインナー巻きとウズラ巻きとロールキャベツがあるんですが…
And, we also have Wiener Roll, Quail Egg Roll, and Cabbage Roll...
こちらは数が少ないです。
These are limited in number.
他が唐揚げと…
Others are Karaage and...
風真家の梅干しおにぎり。
Kazama family's Pickled Plum Rice Ball.
風真いろはのボーダークッキー。
Kazama Iroha's Border Cookie.
そしてロールキャベツ、コンソメ味が限定です。
And Cabbage Roll, Consomme flavor is limited.
というわけで、じゃあおでんは…
So, for the oden...
食べたいぞ…見つけられるかわかんないぞっていう…
Those who want to eat... I don't know if you can find it though...
じゃあまつり先輩から。
Then, starting with Matsuri-senpai.
え、何？
Eh, what?
大根と…
Daikon and...
大根下の方に入ってるよ。
Daikon is at the bottom.
卵と…
Egg and...
卵も下の方に入ってるよ。
Egg is also at the bottom.
ちくわと…
Chikuwa and...
ちくわ？ちくわ、ちくわ。
Chikuwa? Chikuwa, chikuwa.
餅巾着と…
Mochi Pouch and...
牛すじと…
Beef Tendon and...
牛すじ！？
Beef Tendon!?
あ、ウズラ巻き。
Ah, Quail Egg Roll.
牛すじ、牛すじ。
Beef Tendon, Beef Tendon.
昆布言ってない。
I didn't say Kelp.
優しく、優しく。
Gently, gently.
今日はFUWAMOCOちゃん実は…
Actually, FUWAMOCO today...
おでんまだ見た目と名前がまだ一致してないものもあるそうなので…
Seems they still haven't matched the looks and names of some oden items...
牛すじちっちゃい！
Beef Tendon is small!
多分ね落ちてる、鍋の中に。
It probably fell into the pot.
食べていいクッキーなの？
Is it a cookie we can eat?
あ、それお皿に開けてもらっていいですか？
Ah, can you open it onto a plate?
はい、クッキー。
Yes, cookie.
It's a cookie!
Yummy!
Yummy yummy yummy yummy.
あ、でっかい！
Ah, huge!
え、美味しそう！
Eh, looks delicious!
ロールキャベツはいかが？
How about a cabbage roll?
ロールキャベツは今、巻きがね...
The cabbage roll, right now the wrapping is...
発見できんかった、鍋の中で。
couldn't be found inside the pot.
沈んでるから。
Because it's sunk.
下の方いったらある可能性あり。
There's a possibility it's at the bottom.
あ、みんな多分これだね。
Ah, everyone, it's probably this one.
あ、それだ。
Ah, that's it.
練り物っぽい。
Looks like a fish cake.
これは、えっと、さつま揚げ？
Is this, um, Satsuma-age?
さつま揚げかも。
Might be Satsuma-age.
あ、こっちもさつま揚げじゃない？
Ah, isn't this one Satsuma-age too?
あ、これか。
Ah, is it this?
いや、さつま揚げ...
No, Satsuma-age...
これです、これ。
It's this, this.
あ、餅巾着じゃない？
Ah, isn't it Mochi-kinchaku?
じゃあみんな、これで。
Then everyone, with this.
あってる？
Is it correct?
オッケー。
Okay.
3秒！
3 seconds!
はい、チーズ。
Say cheese.
完了！
Done!
じゃあ、こちらがご注文の品となります。
Here is your order.
ご注文の品なり。
Your order is here.
じゃあ、このカメラ...
Then, this camera...
私になり、おかわりもあるぞ。
becomes me, and there's seconds too.
おかわり！
Seconds!
あるぞ！
We have it!
カモンカモン！
Come on, come on!
おいでおいで。
Come here, come here.
そっち唐揚げを今...
Over there, the Karaage is now...
あ、唐揚げ！
Ah, Karaage!
唐揚げ！
Karaage!
Karaage too!
唐揚げも食べます。
Will eat Karaage too.
じゃあ二人...
Then, you two...
いろは先輩、お任せお願いします。
Iroha-senpai, I'll leave it to you.
お任せ！
Leave it to me!
今日は実は、先にフワモコに食べてもらったので。
Actually, we had FuwaMoco eat first today.
いつもの！
The usual!
美味しかったやつを、じゃあ入れちゃいましょう。
Then let's put in the ones that were delicious.
え、美味しかったやつ？
Eh, the delicious ones?
全部だ！
That's everything!
全部美味しいから！
Because everything is delicious!
お任せ！
Leave it to me!
Are you hungry?
Hungry, hungry!
You could eat a horse?
Eat a horse?
Horse!?
牛すじかな。
Maybe beef tendon.
Maybe you have eaten...
え、ジジちゃんが食べたことない？
Eh, Gigi-chan hasn't eaten it before?
It's, ah...
おでん初めて？
Oden first time?
Yep, first time!
First time!
でもハンペンがすごい美味しかったから。
But the Hanpen was super delicious.
はんぺんはマストだ。
Hanpen is a must.
はんぺんマストだんと。
Hanpen is must-done.
あと餅巾着がいい。
Also Mochi-kinchaku is good.
ジジちゃんとセシリアちゃんはおでん食べるの初めて？
Is it the first time for Gigi-chan and Cecilia-chan to eat Oden?
First time here!
First time ever!
Wow!
First time here.
人生初！？
First time in life!?
人生初おでん！
First Oden in life!
人生初、おでん。
First time in life, Oden.
人生初おでん。
First Oden in life.
食べてない？
Haven't eaten?
人生初おでん。
First Oden in life.
あずいろが作ったおでんだ。
It's the Oden Azuiro made.
セシリアちゃんは...
Cecilia-chan is...
緊張してきた。
I'm getting nervous.
責任重大よ。
It's a huge responsibility.
初があずいろおでん。
First is Azuiro Oden.
え、嬉しい！
Eh, I'm happy!
人生初。
First time in life.
嬉しいね。
I'm happy.
Yummy Oden for the first time!
餅巾着はスペシャル...
Mochi-kinchaku is special...
Special!
Thank you!
じゃあ行ける？
Then, can you go?
じーじーじーじーのも。
Gi- Gi- Gigi's too.
やったー！
Yay!
大丈夫そう？
Looks okay?
だけどお皿の記憶がまだ食べてない。
But the memory of the plate hasn't eaten yet.
クッキーだけまだ...
Only the cookie is still...
あ、クッキー。
Ah, cookie.
あ、クッキーだね。
Ah, it's a cookie.
Some cookies and...
ライスボール...あ。
Rice ball... ah.
みんなでいただきますしてる。
Everyone is saying Itadakimasu.
唐揚げ。
Karaage.
クッキー美味しい。
Cookie is delicious.
Are you ready?
Ready, ready!
わさびクッキー。
Wasabi cookie.
良かった。
Good.
良かった、良かった。
Good, good.
職人が、じゃあ装っておりますから。
The artisan is serving it now.
職人がやってくれる。
The artisan will do it.
卵もいいの？
Egg is good too?
あ、これでいいの？
Ah, is this okay?
Yummy!
大丈夫そう？
Looks okay?
じゃあ、ジジちゃんのは？
Then, how about Gigi-chan's?
お箸。
Chopsticks.
オッケー。
Okay.
ジジちゃんのはどうだ？
How is Gigi-chan's?
食べてなかったな。
Hasn't eaten yet.
ジジちゃん。
Gigi-chan.
So hot!
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
あー、ありがとう、美味しい！
Ah, thank you, delicious!
じゃあ、えっとジジちゃんには...
Then, um, for Gigi-chan...
さつま揚げ、牛すじ...
Satsuma-age, beef tendon...
卵、餅巾着。
Egg, Mochi-kinchaku.
餅巾着美味しいんだよ。
Mochi-kinchaku is tasty.
熱い！
Hot!
Too hot!
あ、すごい、もち巾着。
Ah, wow, Mochi-kinchaku.
もち巾着美味しいんだよ。
Mochi-kinchaku is tasty.
熱い、too hot.
Hot, too hot.
熱い熱い！
Hot, hot!
Be careful.
Especially egg.
熱い！
Hot!
The eggs are probably really hot, so be careful to burn your mouth.
助かる、翻訳が。
Translation helps.
助かるー。
Helps a lot.
美味し出したの、店主の顔しとる。
Putting on the face of a shop owner who served something delicious.
店主。
Shop owner.
Cecilia... not so hungry.
あ、これでもういいんじゃない？
Ah, isn't this enough already?
でも餅巾着も食べてほしいな。
But I want you to eat Mochi-kinchaku too.
半分こしな、じゃあ。
Split it in half, then.
半分こいいですね。
Half is good.
Can you share with Gigi?
With Gigi?
かわいい。
Cute.
Can you share with Gigi?
あ、ぜひ、もち巾着。
Ah, definitely, Mochi-kinchaku.
OK.
Gigi, we're sharing half.
じゃあちょっと何個か...シェアしていただくということで。
Then, a few... share and eat.
じゃあセシリアのは...
Then Cecilia's is...
卵。
Egg.
おぉー！
Ooh!
こんにゃく。
Konjac.
美味しそう！
Looks delicious!
大根。
Radish.
あとはさつま揚げ、ちくわ。
And Satsuma-age, Chikuwa.
はい。
Yes.
あとは餅巾着が、シェアになります。
And Mochi-kinchaku will be shared.
There's Daikon...
Radish.
こんにゃく。
Konjac.
取り分け係をしてくれて…
She's acting as the server...
Karaage!
Homemade?
Handmade! Yes!
食べます！
I'll eat!
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
Yummy!
おいしい！
Delicious!
Chicken!
卵…
The egg...
Soft!
柔らかい！ふわふわ！
It's soft! Fluffy!
日本語上手で嬉しい…
I'm happy your Japanese is so good...
ござるおじさん嬉しい。
Old Man Gozaru is happy.
ござるおじさん？
Old Man Gozaru?
泣き？
Crying?
昆布…ね。
Kombu (kelp)... right.
昆布好き？
Do you like Kombu?
昆布は…ちょっと…
Kombu is... a little bit...
苦手っていう時もあるから…
Sometimes I'm not good with it...
「コンブチャ」もあるんですよね。
There is also "Kombucha", you know.
海外の「コンブチャ」とかもあって…
Like the "Kombucha" overseas...
違うね。
It's different, isn't it.
昆布茶とKombucha。
Kelp tea and Kombucha.
こぶちゃ？
Kobucha?
違うんだよ。
It's different.
この昆布は大丈夫？
Is this Kombu okay?
大丈夫！
It's okay!
今日は食べてないからちょっと気になる。
I haven't eaten it today so I'm a bit curious.
食べる？
Will you eat it?
食べる！
I'll eat it!
うずら巻きもちょっと…食べてみて。
Try the quail roll too...
What do you think this is?
Fish.
Fish cake?
練り物っていう…
It's called 'nerimono' (fish paste products)...
Yummy! おいしい！
Yummy! Delicious!
え、確か「練り物」って英語で何て言うの？
Eh, wait, how do you say 'nerimono' in English?
Fish cake?
Fish paste? Maybe fish cake.
Paste...
What do you think?
It's yummy! おいしい！
It's yummy! Delicious!
おいしい！
Delicious!
良かった！
I'm glad!
これだけでもう救われた。
I'm already saved just by this.
今日これだけでもう救われている。
I'm already saved just by this today.
Cooking genius!
天才！
Genius!
良かった！
That's great!
ござるおじさん泣いちゃうよ。
Old Man Gozaru is gonna cry.
あと、おにぎりもあるんで…一緒に。
Also, there are rice balls... have them together.
どうぞどうぞ。
Please, go ahead.
あの…うちのスポンサーが…
Um... our sponsor...
スポンサーって名前のうちの実家が…
My parents' home, which goes by the name 'Sponsor'...
色々用意してくれてた…
prepared various things...
という名前の私の家の仕送りです。
It's a care package from my house (by that name).
で作ったおにぎりなんで…
It's rice balls made with that so...
梅干しはござるがやりました。
I (Gozaru) did the pickled plum myself.
梅干しつけてくれてる。
She pickled the plums.
すごっ！
Wow!
梅干しだけござるなんで。
Only the pickled plum was me.
これ今日ですね、この「あずいろ食堂」開店に…
Also today... for this 'Azuiro Diner' opening...
沢山のフラスタを頂きました！
We received many flower stands!
わーー！すごい！
Waaah! Amazing!
え、面白い！
Eh, interesting!
ちょっと見てほしいみんなに！
I want everyone to see this!
見てみたい！
I want to see!
わーー！
Waaah!
すごい！
Amazing!
きれい！
Beautiful!
すごーい！
Amaaaazing!
あの…昨日の製作配信、クッキング配信で…
Um... during yesterday's production/cooking stream...
ござるが「じゃあフラスタ送りたい人はpingでよろしく」って言ったら…
I said 'If you want to send flowers, ping me' and...
こんなことになってしまいました。
It ended up like this.
すごい！
Amazing!
開店祝いありがとうございます！
Thank you for the opening celebration!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
気軽に言ってごめん！
Sorry for saying it so casually!
ありがとうみんな！
Thank you everyone!
本当にこんなにフラスタを送られてくると思わなかったんだ。
I really didn't think I'd get so many flowers sent.
許してくれ。
Please forgive me.
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so muuuch!
や、すごい本当に…
Man, it's really amazing...
回転したーって…
Like 'We opened!'...
うずら巻き！
Quail roll!
え、これうずら巻きかな？
Eh, is this a quail roll?
あ、いわし団子！
Ah, sardine dumpling!
いわし団子！
Sardine dumpling!
いつも忘れてた。
I always forget.
あ、忘れてた！
Ah, you forgot!
え、いわし団子は何？
Eh, what is a sardine dumpling?
Sardines? 魚？
Sardines? Fish?
魚！
Fish!
あーそうなんだ！
Ah, I see!
え、気になる。
Eh, I'm curious.
え、もう食べたい！
Eh, I want to eat it already!
つみれはでも大人の味じゃない？
But isn't tsumire (fish ball) an adult taste?
つみれ？
Tsumire?
大人の味が…
An adult taste...
おいしい！
Delicious!
二人はおでん何が好き？
What do you two like in Oden?
なんこ、魚じゃない？
Like... isn't it fish?
え？
Eh?
魚じゃない？
Isn't it fish?
クタクタな...
It's all stewed and soft...
大人だなー
So mature~
柔らかい昆布食べたい？
You want to eat soft kelp?
まぁでも大根かな？
Well, maybe daikon radish?
お茶食べて...？
Eat the tea...?
何かござるさんは？
What about Gozaru-san?
子供のころは...
When I was a child...
古の母親と卵を奪い合いました。
I fought over eggs with my ancient mother.
あ、卵おいしい！
Ah, eggs are delicious!
卵を取り合いました。
We fought over the eggs.
Egg!
おいしい！
It's delicious!
Delicious!
モッコリ先輩何が好き？おでんは？
Moccori-senpai, what do you like in Oden?
餅巾着！
Mochi Kinchaku!
あるよ！
We have it!
That's the mochi... FWMC bag!
あれ？いるやん！
Huh? It's in there!
いるやん！
It's there!
おいしそうや！
Looks delicious!
Yeah, true!
That's my favorite one.
And then the hanpen too...
What do you think of the hanpen?
What's the hanpen?
That's what you're eating!
Oh! Oishii!
Oh! Delicious!
おいしい！よかった！
Delicious! That's good!
Texture...
昆布... 昆布 seaweed.
Kelp... Kelp seaweed.
It's really good too!
It has a lot of flavor, umami!
うま味！
Umami!
I really like the egg.
You like it?
Egg, 卵, yeah.
Egg, tamago, yeah.
好き？
Like it?
好き！
I like it!
What's the texture?
あ、食感！食感教えて！
Ah, shokkan! Tell us the texture!
確かに、ふわふわ？
True, is it fluffy?
Yeah, fluffy!
すごいよ！
It's amazing!
え、はんぺんははんぺんで伝わらないよな？
Eh, 'hanpen' doesn't translate as just 'hanpen', right?
伝わらない！
It doesn't translate!
Is it hanpen fish cake?
Fish cake?
全部がフィッシュケーキだから！そうちょっと...
Everything is a fish cake! Yeah, kinda...
そうなんです、みなさん。練り物はまとめてフィッシュケーキって言うらしいです。
That's right, everyone. It seems all paste products are collectively called 'fish cake'.
フィッシュケーキ！
Fish cake!
いっぱい種類があるけどね。
Though there are many types.
そうねー。
Right~.
わかめも...？
Seaweed too...?
きのこもそうだっけ？
Mushrooms too, right?
全部マッシュルーム。
Everything is 'mushroom'.
そうなんだ！
Is that so!
The wakame seaweed...
へー！
Heeh!
Konbu seaweed.
らしいです、みなさん。
Apparently so, everyone.
Enoki mushroom.
全部マッシュルーム。
All 'mushroom'.
そういう風に名前が付くんだ。
So that's how they're named.
これが文化の違いかと思います。
I guess this is the cultural difference.
What do you think of the soup? Dashi wa?
What do you think of the soup? How's the broth?
うん！
Yeah!
おいしい！おいしい！
Delicious! Delicious!
It's good over rice!
Mecha mecha flavor!
So much flavor!
味が一杯ある？
Lots of flavor?
It's good over rice!
フレーバー、味が、いい！
Flavor, the taste is good!
あ、Flavor!
Ah, Flavor!
味！
Taste!
Mecha mecha aji!
So much taste!
味、おいしい！
Taste, delicious!
よかった！
Glad to hear it!
今日はカツオ。
Today is bonito.
麺つゆちょっと。
A little noodle soup base.
なんか効いてる！
Something's working in it!
あ、ちょっと効いてる。あと白だし。
Ah, it's working a bit. Also white dashi.
昆布！
Kelp!
So in the soup there's...
Konbu seaweed...
Kelp seaweed...
White dashi stock...
And this...
Mentsuyu...
Noodle soup base...
麺つゆ！
Mentsuyu!
他には...？
Anything else...?
キャベツ入れたっけな？
Did I put cabbage in?
いや、でも朝仕込んだのはそれだけ。
No, but that's all I prepped this morning.
And then everything else is good over rice!
Lots of love into it!
That's the... what's mochi kinchaku?
Yeah yeah yeah yeah!
餅巾着！
Mochi Kinchaku!
Eating from the top, the mochi is at the bottom!
Treasure!
熱そう...
Looks hot...
The love...
出てるから。
Because it's coming out.
見てる...
She's watching...
The dog...
The dog?!
ござるん、驚愕してるよ。
Gozaru-n is shocked.
なんか結構もう減ってない？
Hasn't it gone down quite a bit already?
まつり先輩結構食べてく...
Matsuri-senpai ate quite a lot...
One night!
One night only!
お代わり？
Seconds?
え、でもまだ来るかもしれないから。
Eh, but more people might still come.
こないだもね、足りなくなったから。
Last time we ran out too.
ちょっと怖いから。
So I'm a little scared.
いっぱい食べてほしい！
I want you to eat a lot!
今日はクリスマスの時と違って、みんなほら...
Unlike Christmas, today everyone is...
スタジオいないから。
Not in the studio.
そう、今日はね。
Right, today.
今日はスタジオにね。
In the studio today.
もうちょっと様子見るね？
I'll wait and see a bit more, okay?
流石にね、もう二回目やったら怒られちゃうから。
Naturally, if it happens a second time I'll get scolded.
いや嬉しい、めっちゃ食べてくれるの。
I'm so happy you're eating so much.
いやよかったでーす。
I'm glad.
あんま聞き食べなくて大丈夫？
Are you okay not eating much?
え、でもさっき食べたしね。今日ね朝ごはんに食べたから。
Eh, but I ate earlier. I ate it for breakfast today.
我々は朝ご飯、おでんでした。
Our breakfast was Oden.
味見がてらね。
Just tasting it.
What do you think of the mochi?
Doughnut?
Mochi!
Really good! Oishii!
Really good! Delicious!
Senpai!
Akachan!
Baby!
Gigi-chan, akachan, she can't eat.
Gigi-chan is a baby, she can't eat.
結構顔についてるね。
It's all over her face.
She's she's baby!
Such a baby!
Cute!
ジジちゃんとセシリアちゃんは凸待ち自体が...
For Gigi-chan and Cecilia-chan, a call-in wait itself is...
そう！
Yes!
初めてです！
First time!
初めての凸待ち！
First call-in wait!
First time ever coming to one of the call-ins!
We are so lucky!
We got food!
So happy thank you!
からしとかもあったの？
Was there mustard too?
あ、あります！
Ah, yes there is!
あ、そう、からし！
Ah, right, mustard!
There's also the karashi, spicy mustard too!
Flavor with two!
辛い！好き！
Spicy! I like it!
わさびに似てる味がする？
Does it taste like wasabi?
する？
Does it?
するかな？
Maybe?
しないのかな？
Maybe not?
お腹いっぱい！
I'm full!
Jiji-chan can eat a horse!
まだ食べる？ まだ食べる！
Still eating? Still eating!
まだいっぱい！
There's still a lot!
無理はしないで。
Don't push yourself.
クッキー！ ござるクッキー！
Cookies! Gozaru Cookies!
Cookie cookie cookie cookie!
Jiji-chan can eat.
Do you still have leftovers there?
Oh babe.
It's okay, I can eat it.
You sure you wanna eat it? Okay.
I'll Gozaru cookie too. Yeah.
Yummy!
初めて会った時から、ござるクッキー美味しい！
Since the first time we met, Gozaru Cookies have been delicious!
美味しいって食べてくれて...
Saying they're delicious as you eat them...
嬉しい。
Makes me happy.
Auto-focus is here.
Auto-focus is dead.
Look at this piece of food.
Thank you, you're welcome.
Yeah.
You're not gonna explain to them what it means?
No no no no.
What?
美味しい。
It's delicious.
やばい、嬉しいよ。
Wow, I'm so happy.
言えば持って帰るなんて...
If I say take it home...
うまい。
Good.
中身を...
Here's the inside...
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
気をつけて。
Be careful.
あ、でもまだいっぱいある。
Ah, but there's still a lot.
まだあるよ！
There's still more!
だってめっちゃ作ったもん。
Because I made a ton.
食べたいんですよね？
You want to eat it, right?
Hey, hey, listen close!
食べたいっていう顔つきで来て...
You came here with a face saying you want to eat...
いいですよ。
Fine.
あと10分だけ待ってやる！
I'll wait just 10 more minutes!
あと10分だけ待ってやる。
I'll wait just 10 more minutes.
10分だけ待ってくれるそうなんで。
Seems she'll wait just 10 minutes.
全然いい、どうぞ。
It's totally fine, go ahead.
10分だけ待ったっていい。
I'm okay with waiting just 10 minutes.
10分だけ待ってくれる。
She'll wait just 10 minutes.
なんかおまじないかけた方が良かったかなと。
I thought maybe we should have cast a spell on it.
おまじない！確かに！
A spell! Indeed!
やってもらえる！？
You'll do it for us!?
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, Oden, Kyun!
私も食べる！
I'll eat too!
カメラさん、こっち来て！
Camera-san, come here!
あー撮ってくれる。
Ah, they're filming.
なんかはんぺんの形で...
In the shape of a hanpen fish cake...
はんぺんの形？
Shape of a hanpen?
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, Oden, Kyun!
Kawaii!
Cute!
It's not on all of the meals though?
あ、もう一回？
Ah, one more time?
今の practice？
Was that practice?
You have to do the Oden Oden Kyun.
Ah, you want Oden Oden Kyun.
Okay, okay.
やるんだな。
They're doing it.
カメラさん、こっち。
Camera-san, over here.
カメラさんお願いします。
Camera-san, please.
Okay, here we go.
Wait, wait, AZKi-senpai.
Okay, okay.
おでん、おでん...
Oden, Oden...
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, Oden, Kyun!
可愛い！
So cute!
すごい！
Amazing!
良く出ちゃった、私。
I really put myself out there.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はんぺんの形で...
In the shape of a hanpen...
おでん、おでんキュン！
Oden, Oden Kyun!
これが一番うまい出汁だろ。
This is definitely the best soup stock.
出汁、美味しくなる。
The stock becomes delicious.
これを商品化...
Commercialize this...
また無しで。
Not without it again.
これをお願いできない？
Can't we request this?
おでんキュン！
Oden Kyun!
以上、ここ、浪速おでん。
That's all, here, Naniwa Oden.
これをセットとして買わないと売ってくれないとか。
Like they won't sell it unless you buy this as a set.
ボイス付きで！
With voice!
エキスポで！
At the Expo!
やってほしい！
We want you to do it!
やってほしい、ボイス付き！
We want it, with voice!
おでん、おでんキュン、ボイス！
Oden, Oden Kyun, Voice!
あ、聞こう。
Ah, let's ask.
ボイス付き、QRコードカードとか。
QR code card with voice, etc.
QRコード！読み込んだら...
QR code! If you scan it...
読み込んだら美味しくなるやつ。
The kind that becomes delicious when scanned.
今からやらないかな？
Won't they do it starting now?
もう来月はちょっと間に合わない。
It's a bit too late for next month.
間に合わない、無理かな。
Too late, probably impossible.
来年！
Next year!
やってくれ！頼む！カバー！
Do it! Please! Cover!
あずいろ食堂やってよ。
Do it, Azuiro Cafeteria.
あずいろ夫婦してよ。
Do the Azuiro couple.
あ、違うボイスが入ってる。
Ah, there's a different voice in it.
ランダム、ランダム！
Random, random!
ござるボイスはちょっと... この辺で作ったんで、失礼するから。
Gozaru voice is a bit... I made it around here, so excuse me.
ござるボイス苦手。
Not good with Gozaru voice.
いやー確かに、夢広がるな、やっぱ。
Yeah, truly, dreams really expand, huh.
いろんなこうさ、みんなで集まってご飯して...
Like various things, gathering together and eating...
ね、作ったりするのいいよね。
Right, making food is good too.
そこの間の蕎麦もね。
The soba noodles in between too.
でも気づいちゃったのは、多分...
But what I realized is, probably...
この家の皆、蕎麦作ったことないですね。
Everyone in this house has never made soba.
そうなんだ！
Is that so!
蕎麦僕どうやって作るのって...
Like 'How do I make soba?'...
どうやって茹でるの？って。
Like 'How do I boil it?'
ホロ蕎麦。
Holo Soba.
Having us soba noodles, boy.
If you made it yourself, like you boil the noodles and everything.
や、イカある。
No, there's squid.
あると思う。
I think there is.
そばって「傍」なんだ。スバちゃんの。
Soba means 'beside'. Like Subaru-chan's side.
ね、やっぱスバルだよね。
Right, it's definitely Subaru.
ちょっとこれ言っとく？
Should we mention this?
あの…悲しみの連…
Um... the sad message...
ちょっとさ、だから、ちょっと前にあずいろ食堂ありますってね、
So, a little while ago, we announced Azuiro Shokudo is opening,
あの、みんなにお伝えしたんですけど、
um, we told everyone about it,
えっとね、お知らせして、
and, after announcing it,
１分かかんないうちに、
within less than a minute,
スバちゃんから「行きます！」って来て、
Subaru-chan sent a message saying 'I'm coming!',
来る予定だったんだけど、ちょっと…
she was planning to come, but a little...
ちょっとね、これがあれなっちゃって。
Yeah, this happened unfortunately.
いやでもあんな即レスは久々に。
But I haven't seen such a quick reply in ages.
一番食べたそうにしてた。
She seemed to want to eat it the most.
でしょ。今日も、あのそばの話してたからね。
Right. Since we were talking about soba today too.
聞きたかったね。
I wanted to ask about it.
本当に食べたいのにみたいな。
Like 'I really want to eat it though'.
おでん食べたかったって言ってくれました。
She said she wanted to eat oden.
１分だったんだ。そば会に呼んで。
It was one minute. Let's invite her to a soba party.
で、まつりちゃんが次の返信してくれた。
And Matsuri-chan replied next.
早かったんだ。
It was fast.
スバちゃんとまつりちゃんが「行きます！」くれて。
Subaru-chan and Matsuri-chan said 'I'm coming!'.
AZKiちゃんといろはちゃんに質問だけど、
I have a question for AZKi-chan and Iroha-chan,
What kind of food do you want to eat in Japan if it's like homemade?
オムライス！
Omurice!
オムライス食べてみたいなって。
I'd like to try eating omurice.
食べてみたいなあ。
I want to try it.
それこそメイド喫茶体験しよう。
That's exactly why we should try a maid cafe experience.
メイドでいいですか？
Are you okay with being maids?
自分、厨房で。
I'll be in the kitchen.
What about you, ししろちゃんは？
What about you, Shishiro-chan?
日本の…Homemade Bento。
Japanese... Homemade Bento.
弁当作りたい会とか。
Like a bento making party.
誰のお弁当です？ 彼女弁当？
Whose bento? Girlfriend bento?
彼女弁当！
Girlfriend bento!
コアだな。
That's hardcore.
Whose bento do you want to eat the most?
Everyone here.
先輩達。
Sempais.
まつりも？ まつり先輩も？
Matsuri too? Matsuri-senpai too?
彼女弁当。
Girlfriend bento.
僕の？ いいよ。
Mine? Sure.
みんな、どんな弁当作るんだろう？
I wonder what kind of bento everyone makes?
作ってあげようかな。
Maybe I'll make one for you.
弁当会やったら呼んで。
Invite me if you do a bento party.
これから時期的にお花見で。
From now on, it's flower viewing season.
確かにお花見。
True, flower viewing.
モコちゃんが食ってくれた弁当たくさん食べたんです。
I ate a lot of the bento Moco-chan 'ate' for me.
ちなみにその昔 holoX では、「お子様ランチ選手権」っていうのやったことがあって。
By the way, long ago in HoloX, we did a 'Kid's Lunch Championship'.
似てる。お弁当…お子様ランチ。
It's similar. Bento... Kid's lunch.
HoloX had like a event where they had to make like okosama lunch, kind of kid's lunch.
And that's like omurice and stuff.
お弁当の中にオムライス入れれるしね。
You can put omurice in a bento too.
We should all eat together and then picnic.
Picnic!
花見だね。
It's flower viewing.
Yeah, hanami together.
またね、クリスマスにおでんも言って、今日がありますので。
We also mentioned oden at Christmas, and that led to today.
最後にふわわちゃんが来てくれて。
Fuwawa-chan came at the end.
おでん食べて…
Eating oden...
食べ物が目的で来たんじゃない？
Didn't you come just for the food?
大丈夫！
It's fine!
食べ物が目的でも…
Even if food is the goal...
唐揚げもね、ちょっと準備して。
We prepared fried chicken too.
食べてもらいました。
We had you eat it.
唐揚げどうですか？
How is the fried chicken?
唐揚げおいしい！
Fried chicken is delicious!
今回大きいよね。
It's big this time, right?
まだ３つしか食べてないよ。
I've only eaten three.
１個シェアしました。
We shared one.
１個しか食べてないの？
You only ate one?
１個シェアした。
We shared one.
大きいから。
Because it's big.
何を言っているんだみたいな顔…
She's making a face like 'what are you saying'...
おもろいからちょっとやめてほしい。
It's funny so I want you to stop.
おでんもシェアしましたから。
Because we shared the oden too.
まだ今日は全然食べてはない。
We haven't eaten much at all today yet.
あの、カメラのこっち側というか、こっち側なんですけど
Umm, on this side of the camera, or rather, over here...
まあ、あの、普通ここね、人がいるものとして想定していないので
Well, normally, we don't expect anyone to be standing here, so...
あ、こっちにお願いします。
Ah, over here, please.
あの、後ろでうちのスタッフがみんな控えてます。
Umm, all of our staff are waiting behind us.
おでんを食べたくて。
They want to eat oden.
あー、オッケー！
Ah, okay!
そんなこと言われちまったら...
If you say it like that...
AZKi先輩、何がいいですか？
AZKi-senpai, what would be good?
こんにゃく！
Konnyaku!
オッケー！
Okay!
Konnyaku coming up!
こんにゃく...
Konnyaku...
多分ね、売り切れてるものも、具材によってはちょっと少ないものもあるかも。
Some ingredients might be sold out or running low.
言ったほうがいいですね。
I should probably mention that.
あ、こんにゃく！
Ah, konnyaku!
こんにゃく！
Konnyaku!
Yes, get that!
こんにゃく！
Konnyaku!
こんにゃくilだけ？
Just konnyaku?
悩んでる、悩んでる。
They're thinking about it.
Thinking.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
はんぺん、オッケー！
Hanpen, okay!
あるある、はんぺん。
We have hanpen.
はんぺん！はんぺん！
Hanpen! Hanpen!
あったかーい、やつ。
A nice warm one.
Okay, we got it.
はんぺん、ください。
Hanpen, please.
あ、2枚、2枚。
Ah, two pieces, two pieces.
うちのはんぺん、ちょっとちっちゃいけど。
Our hanpen is a bit small though.
あ、いいよ。
Ah, that's fine.
ください、ください。
Please, please.
オッケー。
Okay.
出汁いっぱいで！
Lots of soup!
出汁いっぱいw
Lots of soup, haha.
可愛いw
So cute, lol.
Like a soundboard...
可愛い、可愛い！
Cute, cute!
手伝いたい。
I want to help.
可愛い。
Cute.
出汁いっぱい？あ、じゃあそれくらいで。
Lots of soup? Ah, that much is good.
Thank you!
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ、いっぱいい出しとくね。
Then, I'll pour a lot.
ちょっとフーフーして。
Please blow on it a little.
あ、あつ、熱い？
Ah, h-hot?
あじゃ、ここに置きます。ここに置きます。
Okay, I'll put it here. Putting it here.
え、フーフー？
Eh, blow on it?
え、で、どうしよう。
Eh, w-what should we do.
二人... 持って、持って！
Two of us... hold it, hold it!
え、持って？
Eh, hold it?
あ、大丈夫、ここは持てた。
Ah, it's okay, I've got it here.
横から、横どうし、せーの、フーフーして！
From the side, side by side, ready, blow on it!
すごいことやらせますねw
You're making us do something incredible, lol.
Service!
そこまでやる？
Do we go that far?
Service, service!
フーフー。
Fuu-fuu.
せーの！
Ready, go!
フーー、フーー！
Fuu~, Fuu~!
わーー！
Waaaah!
あったかいから。
Because it's warm.
わーーーい！
Yaaaay!
おでん、おでんキュン？
Oden, oden-kyun?
食堂ってこういう感じだったっけ？
Was the cafeteria always like this?
美味しくなーれ！
Become delicious!
おでん、おでん、キュン！
Oden, oden, kyun!
わーーー！ありがとうございまーす！
Waaaah! Thank you very much!
はいよー！
Here you go!
ありがとね。
Thanks.
また来ましたよ！
We're here again!
How are you doing?
Do you want to eat more?
え、こういう感じでいいの？
Eh, is this style okay?
お腹いっぱい、でも...
We're full, but...
Vegetables, vegetables!
Vegetables!
ちょっと別な日本語...
Some other Japanese...
ごめん、こんな感じだったっけ？
Sorry, was it always like this?
食堂...
The cafeteria...
ここサービスがいいですね！
The service here is great!
サービスが素晴らしい！
The service is wonderful!
サービス精神強いw
Strong spirit of service, lol.
サービス精神...うわー、僕ちゃん。
Spirit of service... Whoa, boy.
いい店だぜ！
This is a great shop!
メイド食堂になっちゃったw
It's turned into a Maid Cafeteria, lol.
今日だけメイド喫茶。
Maid Cafe, just for today.
うん！
Yeah!
どうする？食堂じゃなくてメイド喫茶。
What do we do? It's not a cafeteria, it's a Maid Cafe.
Kiss!
Kiss?! No!
Service, service! Kiss!
おねがいしまーす！
Pleeease!
え、何何？何て？食堂、普通の食堂！
Eh, what what? What did they say? It's a cafeteria, a normal cafeteria!
過激派の食堂w
A radical cafeteria, lol.
はい、行きますよー！
Okay, here we go!
Maid kiss!
壊れているw
They're broken, lol.
Kiss!
行きますよー！
Here we go!
Service, service!
た、頼まれてないけど...！
W-we didn't even ask for this...!
いいですよー！
It's fine!
おでん、おでんキュンする？
Do the oden, oden-kyun?
うーー、萌え萌え...
Uhh, moe moe...
Kiss!
セクハラ？
Sexual harassment?
They harass our workers!
ダメよー！
Don't do that!
No kiss!
三年バイバイするよ？三年バイバイ。
We'll do the 'Three-Year Bye-Bye' you know? Three-Year Bye-Bye.
あらよー！
Alriiiight!
ああー！
Aaaah!
あらよー！よしよしよし。
Alriiiight! Good good good.
So picky about it.
How do we get them to do it?
Why are you saying?!
How about a... how about an air kiss?
Ah!
Air kiss!
Blow kiss!
投げキッス？
Blown kiss?
投げキッスなら...！
If it's a blown kiss...!
待って！
Wait!
大丈夫って！
I said it's okay!
投げキッス？！
Blown kiss?!
違うんだ！
That's not it!
助けて！
Help me!
お戯れです！
They're just playing!
Can you tell them...
ちょっとGoogle...
A little Google...
We'll leave a good review on Google.
Ah, yeah!
Good review!
投げキッスしてくれたら、Googleのレビュー...
If you blow us a kiss, the Google review...
Five stars, kissu!
Five stars!
No kissu, zero star!
投げキッスなかったらゼロ！
If no blown kiss, zero stars!
嘘でしょ？！
You're kidding?!
そんなんで決まるの？！
That's what decides it?!
危ない！
Watch out!
待って！
Wait!
味で、味で！
The taste! Judge by the taste!
味で勝負！味で勝負だ！
We compete with taste! Taste is the key!
Lip fighting is the flavor?!
Fighting?
Yeah, that's what we put our most effort in.
Not air kisses that we blow.
でも、でも、レビューは...
But, but, the review...
Customer service!
AZKi先輩が、AZKi先輩行ってくれる！
AZKi-senpai, AZKi-senpai will do it!
先輩、行ってる？
Senpai, you going?
星5いっぱい来てる！
Lots of 5 stars coming in!
Ah, yeah!
Matsu is supposed to give us all the good ratings.
Oh...
Sing it!
Next time, next time.
Yeah, next customer.
えー？！
Eeeh?!
いつからここはメイド喫茶だと錯覚していたんだ。
Since when were you under the illusion that this was a Maid Cafe?
Ah, ramen!
おじ多くない？
Aren't there a lot of old men?
この麺、おじが多いんじゃ...
These noodles, there's a lot of old men...
心にみんなおじさんを飼っている。
We all have an old man living in our hearts.
おじさんを飼ってるw
Keeping an old man inside, lol.
Yes!
ま、でもいいの、五つ星ね。
Well, it's fine. Five stars.
美味しい！
It's delicious!
Five stars!
あ、ありがとうございまーす！
Ah, thank you very much!
Five stars!
Yeah, lucky!
じゃあ、ござるもちょっとやってもらおうかな。
Then, maybe I'll have Gozaru do it too.
牛すじ食べます！
I'll eat the beef tendon!
The restaurant was really good, the food was really good...
...the flavor was all there.
今のうちに、ちょっとやってもらおう。
Let's have them do it while we can.
今のうちに？
While we can?
ちょっとやってもらっていい？
Can we have you do it a little?
フワモコさんも、自分が作った料理に...
Fuwamoco-san too, for the food you made...
ピンクやってもらっちゃおうかな。
I think we'll have you do the pink one.
Okay good, 牛すじ！
Okay good, beef tendon!
あとは？
What else?
今度、牛すじと...
Next, beef tendon and...
フワロジさんも...
Fuwaroji-san too...
大根あるか？
Is there radish?
大根あった！
Found the radish!
あ、こっちね。
Ah, this one.
心にオジを飼っている...
Keeping an old man (Oji) in your heart...
美味しそう〜！
Looks delicious!
三ついただきました。
We received three.
オッケー！
Okay!
おかしい...
Funny...
おでんもっと入れる？
Want more Oden?
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
おでん今日もやってもらわないと、一回ね。
We have to have them do the Oden magic today too, just once.
今からみんな、これに今から...
Now everyone, to this right here...
やってもらうから。
...we'll have them do it.
撮るね、みんな。
Take a picture, everyone.
じゃあ頼めるか？フワモコ。
Can we ask you then? FUWAMOCO.
オッケー！
Okay!
はい！
Yes!
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
ん〜！力入れますね、ちょっと待って。
Nn~! Putting power in, wait a second.
え、力込めてくれる？
Eh, you're putting power into it?
おじさん嬉しくなっちゃうな。
The old man in me is getting happy.
よし。
Alright.
俺、ここの店主やってて良かった...
I'm glad I'm the owner of this shop...
オッケー！
Okay!
店主の特権だよ。
It's the owner's privilege.
いいやん！
Nice!
オッケー、オッケー！
Okay, okay!
行きますよ！
Here we go!
美味しくな〜れ！
Become delicious!
おでん、おでん、キュ〜ン！
Oden, Oden, Kyu~n!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
や〜ん！
Ya~n!
いいのかこれ？
Is this okay?
うん、食べて食べて。
Yeah, eat, eat.
ここで捌かれたりしない？
We won't get chopped up here, right?
ジューシー...
Juicy...
お腹いっぱい！
I'm full!
あ、いっぱい？
Ah, full?
結構今日、みんなお仕事がいっぱいで...
Today everyone has quite a lot of work...
後ろの時間から来る人が...
...and people are coming in the later slots...
スタッフさんもいますし。
...and the staff is here too.
そうなんだ！
Is that so!
じゃあもう...
Then we'll just...
ごちそうさま！美味しい！
Thanks for the meal! It's delicious!
美味しかったで〜す！
It was delicious!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
美味しい！
Delicious!
美味しかった！
It was tasty!
明太...
Mentai...
My favorite was the... the soft...
What was it?
The Hanpen?
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
はんぺん頭に...
Hanpen on the head...
はんぺんですね。
It's Hanpen, isn't it.
あ、クッキー！
Ah, cookies!
クッキーも好き！
I like the cookies too!
それはいいじじい...
That's a good old man...
Everything was so yummy.
全部？
Everything?
うん！
Yeah!
よかった〜！
I'm glad!
Hard to pick... たまご。
Hard to pick... egg.
たまご！餅巾着が...
Egg! The mochi purse is...
餅巾着！
Mochi purse!
一番好きだった！
I liked it the best!
米は？
What about rice?
食べます？
Will you eat some?
No...
後で来るんだって、人が。
They said people are coming later.
オッケー、オッケー！
Okay, okay!
でもまだ、まだいっぱいありますから。
But there's still, still a lot left.
つもりで...
Intending to...
本当に全然スタッフさんに振る舞うつもりで。
Really intending to serve the staff quite a bit.
あ、そういうことか。
Ah, is that so.
多分フワモコに「萌え萌えキュン」してもらったやつは...
The ones FUWAMOCO did 'Moe Moe Kyun' on are probably...
とっても美味いぞ、みんな。
Very delicious, everyone.
愛情がこもったおでんなのか。
Is it Oden filled with love?
今度から全部...
From now on, everything...
愛情ばかり入れてもらおうかな。
Maybe I'll just have you put love into it.
大事！
It's important!
愛情ばかり大事だよな。
Only love is important, right.
ござるの中のおじさんが目覚めそう。
The old man inside Gozaru looks like he's waking up.
もう目覚めてるけど。
He's already awake though.
目覚めちゃった！
He woke up!
Wow, カワイイ！
Wow, cute!
作ってみるのもやりたいな。
I want to try making it too.
やりたいです！
I want to do it!
申し訳ない...
I'm sorry...
フワモコ給仕するだけで...
FUWAMOCO was just serving...
やった！
Yay!
フワモコがゲームやってた...
FUWAMOCO was playing games...
ああ言うよ...
Ah, she says it...
先輩たちが作ってる間にゲームやってて...
Playing games while the senpais were cooking...
何もやってない！
We didn't do anything!
何作りたい？
What do you want to make?
なんか、こういう食べ物作りたい。
Like, I want to make this kind of food.
逆に何食べたいか聞いて、作ってもらう？
Conversely, should we ask what they want to eat and have them make it?
ザ・フワモコで、練り物も作ってみたい。
As 'The FUWAMOCO', I want to try making paste products too.
おでんが好きだから。
Because I like Oden.
すご！
Wow!
一旦工場行こうか、一緒に。
Let's go to a factory for a bit, together.
工場、工場だね。
Factory, it's a factory.
かまぼこ工場。
Kamaboko factory.
あと、お味噌作りたいな。
Also, I want to make miso.
作りたいね、味噌！
I want to make it, miso!
壺に、投げ入れるんですよね？
You throw it into a jar, right?
壺に投げるんですよね？
You throw it into a jar, don't you?
味噌の玉を...
The miso balls...
元から作りたい！
I want to make it from scratch!
番組で。
On a show.
あと、梅干しも作ってみたい。
Also, I want to try making dried plums.
あと納豆！
And natto!
フワモコに何作ってもらいたいですか？
What do you want me to make for FUWAMOCO?
If we were to cook something, what would you want us to eat?
What would you want us to make for you?
You too?
Yeah.
Us?
うーん...
Hmm...
What is it?
冗談、冗談！
Just kidding, just kidding!
Chocolate... Pralines...?
What's pralines?
Like... fancy candy?
What's the word for romantic chocolate?
ロマンチックチョコレート？
Romantic chocolate?
本命チョコ？
Honmei choco (true love chocolate)?
本命チョコ！
Honmei choco!
少女漫画に毒されすぎじゃない？
Aren't you too obsessed with shoujo manga?
ドーナツ... ドーナツって...
Donuts... Donuts are...
どうなってもいいね...
Whatever happens is fine...
Fried donuts... right?
実話...？
True story...?
作りたくない！作りたくない！
I don't want to make them! I don't want to make them!
事故っちゃう？
Will there be an accident?
ドーナツ作れるの？すごい！
You can make donuts? Wow!
揚げ物は怖いよ！
Fried food is scary!
揚げドーナツもある...
There are also fried donuts...
揚げないドーナツ...
Non-fried donuts...
揚げないドーナツは、ちょっと違う...
Non-fried donuts are a bit different...
あ、違う？
Ah, different?
やっぱ揚げないと！
You have to fry them!
If you don't fry donuts, they're not donuts, right?
Donuts are fried... right?
Are those donuts to you?
That's just cake.
Once they're not fried...
No fried donuts... are just cake!
Cake donuts!
揚げてないドーナツは、ただのケーキ。
Non-fried donuts are just cake.
揚げてないドーナツは、ただのケーキだ！
Non-fried donuts are just cake!
美味しいけど、ドーナツじゃないよね。
It's tasty, but it's not a donut.
時々、なんか開拓者んずが...
Sometimes, the Pioneers (Ruffians)...
「ドーナツ作ってみました！」ってみて...
...try to show me "I made donuts!"...
なんかキッチン揚げてくれるんですね、写真。
...and they show a photo of their fried kitchen.
大丈夫だったかな？
I wonder if they were okay?
なんかダメだったけど...
It seemed like it went wrong...
事故ってないかな？
Was it an accident?
そう、心配になっちゃう。
Yeah, I get worried.
爆発しちゃってない？
Did it explode?
ドーナツ揚げるのは事故らない...
Frying donuts doesn't cause accidents...
安全第一！
Safety first!
大丈夫だよ。
It's okay.
ドーナツは...
Donuts are...
じゃあ今度作ると危ないわ。
Then it's dangerous to make them next time.
焼きドーナツね。
Baked donuts then.
私、ハンバーグがいい！
I want hamburger steak!
ハンバーグ！
Hamburg!
フワモコに...
For FUWAMOCO...
練ってくれるかな？
Will you knead it for us?
ね！豆腐？チキン？
Hey! Tofu? Chicken?
チキンの...
Chicken's...
ハンバーグ作るんですね。
You're making hamburg.
チキンではなく... 多分...
Not chicken... maybe...
こねた？
Kneaded?
スプレッドして欲しいって。
She wants it spread.
こねて欲しい。
She wants it kneaded.
手で？
By hand?
なんかちょっと引かれてる...
I think they're a bit put off...
Do you want us to make a hamburger with our bare hands?
No, 本命チョコ！
No, Honmei choco!
本命チョコ！
Honmei choco!
すごい変わりよう...
What a sudden change...
彼女に毒されてる人たち...
People poisoned by their girlfriends...
設定に毒されてる...
Poisoned by the setting...
Next time... I like making cake. So I make you German Cake.
美味しそう！
Sounds delicious!
German cake?
私、シュヴァルツヴァルダー・キルシュトルテ作るの好きだから。
I like making Schwarzwälder Kirschtorte.
What is it like... the cake?
I can make, um, Schwarzwälder Kirschtorte.
What?
Ah, Cherry choco cake.
美味しいやつだ！
That's the tasty one!
Or the... Baumkuchen?
バウムクーヘン！
Baumkuchen!
くるくるしてるやつ？
The swirly one?
でも homemade is just... ch-ch-ch-ch-ch.
But homemade is just... ch-ch-ch-ch-ch.
ちょっと小さい方...
The slightly smaller one...
そう、なんかくるくるしてないね。
Yeah, it's not really swirly.
くるくる... じゃない。でも...
Not... swirly. But...
Choco, choco, choco, choco...
かわいいよね。
It's cute.
レイヤー入れてるんだ。
You put layers in it.
すごい！
Amazing!
So we have to meet again.
あ、絶対！
Ah, definitely!
ね、次会うときは...
Hey, next time we meet...
What else are you gonna bring for everyone next time?
Yes, waffles!
食べたいよ！
I want to eat them!
Can I make anymore?
For everyone here?
教えて欲しい。
I want you to teach me.
バウムクーヘン...
Baumkuchen...
あ、いいえ...
Ah, no...
Did you cook anything?
I'm not good at anything!
I'm a loser!
Hey, I'll make you guys American Mac and Cheese.
Oh!
The eggs...?
Can I tell a story?
日本にはあるかな？
Do they have it in Japan?
Too long of a story...
Mac and Cheese...?
ジャンクフードですか？
Is it junk food?
コメント...
Comments...
みんな教えて...
Everyone tell us...
マカロニ？
Macaroni?
マカロニ！
Macaroni!
I don't like cheese.
あー、チーズ！
Ah, cheese!
マカロニ！
Macaroni!
Mac and Cheese... ないぞ。
Mac and Cheese... we don't have it.
聞いた時ある。
I've heard of it.
Are you gonna make box?
No, I'll make the actual Mac and Cheese.
Main meal, dessert.
チョコ？
Choco?
We don't want it...
Home made?
Home made... one?
Not the box!
I like the box!
なんかね、箱から出すけど...
Like, we take it out of the box but...
ちょっとジャンクフードなイメージあるですね。
It has a bit of a junk food image.
箱から出して、ドンドーン！って。
Take it out of the box and BAM! BAM!
ドンドン！
BAM! BAM!
だけどジジちゃんが作るのは、なんか...
But what Gigi-chan makes is like...
愛を込めて...
filled with love...
Home made チョコ？
Home made choco?
本命！
Honmei! (True Feeling)
本命チョコ！
Honmei Choco!
Home made... yeah! 本命チョコ！
Home made... yeah! Honmei Choco!
Trade! Trade!
Trade?
ああ、本命が大事なんだ。
Ah, so 'Honmei' is what's important.
本命がね！
The 'Honmei' part!
なるほど、本命チョコがいいんだ。
I see, so you want 'True Feeling' chocolate.
Yummy! 美味しい！
Yummy! Delicious!
大好き！
We love it!
I skipped sleep... baby just go to bed.
Okay, they want us to leave.
No, no! I just want...
I just want a kiss!
While I get out of here!
Get out of here!
ほんま、本命欲しがられるの初めてだ。
Wow, it's the first time someone wanted 'Honmei' so much.
食堂でキスを求められるとは！
To think we'd be asked for a kiss at the diner!
特殊です！
This is unique!
Cafeteria want a kiss, what do you need?
Only we gotta kiss!
Just a blow kiss!
I really wanted a kiss!
ものすごくキスが欲しいらしい。
Seems they really, really want a kiss.
絶対違うでしょ！
That's definitely wrong!
チョコ先向いたの今！
You turned to Choco-saki just now!
絶対違うでしょ！
That's definitely wrong!
一番違うでしょ！
That's the most wrong one!
Chu!
KYAAAAAAA!!
ありがとうございましたー！！
Thank you very muuuuch!!
これでいいんだ！？
Is this okay?!
Five star!
全部忘れちゃった！
I forgot everything!
忘れちゃった、まつり先輩！
I forgot, Matsuri-senpai!
It was a real kiss!
やっぱ最後はキスだった。
So it was a kiss in the end.
See you later everyone!
I got a real kiss!
顔でっか！
Huge face!
忘れちゃった。
I forgot.
本命キスカウンターが。
The 'Honmei Kiss' counter.
上がりました。
It went up.
まつり先輩！
Matsuri-senpai!
いい匂い！
Nice smell!
日本語が上手だ。
Their Japanese is good.
そして。
And...
ドキドキ！
Doki doki! (Heart pounding)
キスしちゃいましたからね。
Because we kissed them.
眠い！
Sleepy!
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
皆さん、バイバイ！
Everyone, bye bye!
みんな、バイバイ！
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
Chu chu chu chu!
Kiss you, bau baau!
嬉しいよ。
I'm happy.
忘れ物があるか？
Something left behind?
スマホってこと？
You mean a smartphone?
もしかしてフワモコの？
Is it FUWAMOCO's?
いやでも今日はね、風真先にもいっぱいいてたからね。
But today, Kazama-saki also had a lot of people.
行きたいのに、いけない...
I want to go, but I can't...
行きたいのに行けない日本へ。
To Japan, where they want to go but can't.
楽しかったな。
That was fun.
なんか風邪も流行ってる...
It seems colds are going around...
ねー、確かに。
Yeah, true.
いやーよかった。
Man, that was good.
海外ニキ来てくれた！
Overseas bros came!
シシロン食堂は海外メンバーですね。
Shishiron Diner is for overseas members, isn't it.
ね、すごいレア。
Yeah, super rare.
あずちゃんも。
Azu-chan too.
まだ食べれるんですか？
Can you still eat?
クッキー二袋目開けようとして...
Opening the second bag of cookies...
あ、マジ？
Ah, seriously?
だめ？だめ？
No good? No good?
いいよ、大丈夫ですよ。
It's fine, it's okay.
いいですよ、あげてください。
It's fine, please have some.
クッキー大好き！
I love cookies!
そのまま食べても...
Even eating them like that...
ちゃんとご飯あるよ。
There's proper food too.
美味しいよ！
It's delicious!
自分だもんね、いっぱい食べれる。
It's yours, so you can eat a lot.
そうだね。
That's right.
風真のクッキーって常設で売らないの？
Doesn't Kazama's cookie sell permanently?
常設で売らないの？
Sell permanently?
常設で売ってほしいよ。
I want you to sell them permanently.
常設... どっかに販売...
Permanent... sell somewhere...
スタジオに置いとくみたいな。
Like leaving them in the studio.
あ、スタジオで？
Ah, in the studio?
これクッキーこないだ、あのロボ子先輩に...
About these cookies, recently, Roboco-senpai...
レクチャーしていただいたんですけど。
lectured me on them.
今度はまつり先輩の番だなってずっと思ってて。
I've been thinking it's Matsuri-senpai's turn next.
じゃあ、あのお誘いしようと思ってるんですけど。
So, I'm thinking of inviting her.
え、え！？
Eh, eh!?
えっ、100枚！？
Eh, 100 pieces!?
100枚焼く、100枚。
Bake 100 pieces. 100 pieces.
ちなみに前回ですね...
By the way, last time...
ロボ子先輩はめっちゃ頑張って、
Roboco-senpai worked really hard,
「材料とかは全部ロボ子先輩にこれ買ってきてね」って言ってお使いしてもらってやったんですけど、
and I asked her to buy all the ingredients, but...
まつり先輩は「調理器具がない」って聞いて、
when Matsuri-senpai heard we had no cooking tools,
あ、全部買いました。
she bought everything.
「あ、じゃあ行きます！」クッキーの型も買ったし、
"Oh, then I'm coming!" She even bought cookie cutters.
そう、ちゃんと全部揃えてある。
Yes, she gathered everything properly.
もうオーブンもある。
There's even an oven now.
「じゃあ行きます！来てください！」
"Then I'm coming! Please let me come!"
はい、わかりました。
Okay, understood.
やったー！
Yay!
準備ができたということで！
So preparations are complete!
そう、前話したその日に買った、全部。
Right, she bought it all the day we talked.
買ったんだ！
She bought it!
よかった、じゃあ環境整いました。
Good, now the environment is set.
整ってる。
It's all set.
よかった、じゃああの、空いてる日教えてくれたら送ります。
Great. If you tell me your free days, I'll send it.
クッキー講座を。
The cookie course.
クッキー！
Cookie!
フワモコもクッキー食べる？
Do Fuwamoco want to eat cookies too?
社長クッキー？
President Cookie?
うん、食べる！
Yeah, we'll eat!
ちょっとだけこっち側に...
Just a bit to this side...
この分、全部。
This share, all of it.
唐揚げ美味しかった！
The fried chicken was delicious!
めっちゃニンニク味って感じ。
It tasted very garlicky.
あ、ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you very much.
一応今日はですね、
So, for today...
ちょっとどうしても来たかったけど来れなかった人シリーズ。
the series of people who really wanted to come but couldn't.
莉々奈さんに、
Riona-san...
実はこのクッキー型はですね、莉々奈さんにいただいた...
Actually, these cookie cutters were given to me by Riona-san...
「クッキー型で焼いて！」クッキーでした。
...saying "Bake with these!" It was a phantom cookie.
そうだ、紹介ができてなかったんで。
Right, I hadn't been able to introduce them.
そう、莉々奈から貰ったクッキー型なの。
Yeah, it's the cookie cutter I got from Riona.
かわいい！
Cute!
葉っぱとハート、他にもね色々貰ったんだけど、
Leaf and Heart. She gave me others too, but...
今日はサイズ感の都合でこの2つで。
for today's size constraints, I used these two.
もう莉々奈もね、今日来たいって言ってくれたんだけど。
Riona also said she wanted to come today.
みんな来たいのに！
Everyone wants to come!
お仕事とかね、タイミングがね。しかも遅い時間ならいけるんですけど、
Work and timing... And she said "I can come if it's late."
やってますか？とか。
"Are you still open?" she asked.
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうそうそう。
Right, right.
クッキー食べる！
I'll eat the cookie!
おいしい！
Delicious!
クッキーだー！
It's a cookie!
クッキーって一番大きいサイズってどこまでなら焼けるの？
What's the biggest size cookie you can bake?
え、マジでデカければデカいほど大変なんですけど。
Eh, seriously, the bigger it is, the harder it gets.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
夢のクッキー作りたい、まつりは。
Matsuri wants to make a dream cookie.
え、ゴンザ...？
Eh, Gonza...?
このくらいのクッキー焼きたい。
I want to bake a cookie this big.
キャラクッキーみたいな、なんかナイフとかでこうやって型取ったらできる？
Like a character cookie... if you cut it with a knife, can you do it?
あ、できます。
Ah, you can.
ただ焼き時間と温度調節が結構シビアかも。
But baking time and temperature control might be quite strict.
そうなんだ。
I see.
割れちゃいます。
It might crack.
割れる！？
Crack!?
アイシングクッキーは作ったことある。
I've made icing cookies before.
ああ、アイシング！そう！
Ah, icing! Yes!
アイシングだったら結構なんでも大丈夫。
If it's icing, pretty much anything goes.
ヒビとか、結局アイシングしちゃえば...
Cracks and such, if you just icing over them...
隠れるもんね。
They get hidden.
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
えー、作りたいな、でもキャラクッキー。
Eh, I want to make character cookies though.
まあまつりすなら割れてもいいから作ろうかな。
Well, if it's for Matsuris (fans), it's fine if it cracks.
「まつりすなら大丈夫っしょ！」
"If it's Matsuris, it'll be fine!"
「コメント欄のまつりす大丈夫っしょ！」
"The Matsuris in the comments are fine!"
「割れても大丈夫っしょ！」
"It's fine even if it breaks!"
「100人乗っても大丈夫！」みたいな感じで。
"It's fine even if 100 people ride on it!" sort of vibe.
「え、えっ」って言われてますよ。
They are saying "Eh? Eh?".
え？
Eh?
いいんだよ。
It's fine.
いつもそうだから。
It's always like that.
いつもそう扱い受けてるから。
I'm always treated like that.
あ、まつりす...
Ah, Matsuris...
ハーン...
Haa...
泣いてるよ、まつり先輩。
They are crying, Matsuri-senpai.
かわいいね。
Cute.
そっか。
I see.
クッキングまだやる。
We'll do cooking again.
じゃあまつり先輩いろいろ揃えたんだったら、フワモコちゃんもそうだし料理をね。
Since Matsuri-senpai gathered everything, Fuwamoco too... cooking.
あ、したい！
Ah, want to do it!
料理会！
Cooking party!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ちゃんとね、デカい鍋とかもね、なんかいつか使うかなと思って買った。
I actually bought a huge pot too, thinking I'd use it someday.
買ったんだ！
You bought it!
すごい！もっと食べますか？
Amazing! Will we eat more?
え、どうしようかな。でもなんかちょっと遅めに来るメンバーいるんだよね。
Eh, what to do... but some members are coming a bit late.
今日は大丈夫だよ。
Today is fine.
調節して作ってきてる。
I adjusted the amount I made.
なんかこの間は、マジ続出であんなことになるとは思わなくて。
Last time, people kept coming one after another, I didn't expect that.
本当にスタジオにほぼ、集まってたから。
Everyone practically gathered in the studio.
言うてめっちゃ種あるからな。
Though there are a lot of ingredients.
大根、卵、こんにゃく、ちくわ、はんぺん、餅巾着、牛すじ、ウインナー巻きだっけ？
Daikon, egg, konnyaku, chikuwa, hanpen, mochi-kinchaku, beef tendon, wiener roll?
いわしの...
Sardine...
そうね、いわしの。
Right, sardine's...
いわし団子？
Sardine dumpling?
団子、つみれ？
Dumpling, fish ball?
あ、ロールキャベツ。
Ah, roll cabbage.
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, really!
キャベツ...？キャベツ苦手なんだ？
Cabbage...? Are you bad with cabbage?
火を通した野菜が食べれなくて。
I can't eat cooked vegetables.
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, is that so!
生は好きなんだけど。
I like raw ones though.
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
じゃあ、うちらでやる？一旦さ、おでんロールキャベツ実施しよう。
Then, shall we do it? Let's implement Oden Roll Cabbage once.
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
美味しいっていうよね、でも。
They say it's delicious, though.
やってみます。
We'll try.
こないだコンソメは食べたんです。
I ate consomme ones recently.
じゃあちょっと、ロールキャベツを入れてもらっていいですか？
Then, can you include Roll Cabbage please?
あ、それはちょっと...
Ah, that is a bit...
我々見て回るんで。
We will just watch.
ロールキャベツ、ちょっとロール、ロールロール。
Roll Cabbage, just roll, roll roll.
ロールキャベツは、なんか元々日本のものかなって思って。
I thought Roll Cabbage was originally Japanese.
あー、どうなんだろう。
Ah, I wonder.
え、そうなの？
Eh, is it?
でもなんかクッキングママにあったから、そういうイメージがある。
But it was in Cooking Mama, so I have that image.
あ、そうなんだ！
Ah, is that so!
クッキングママが日本のもの？
Is Cooking Mama Japanese?
これで大丈夫ですか？
Is this okay?
というわけで、我々ですね、このロールキャベツ…
So, regarding our cabbage rolls...
え、おでん出汁ロールキャベツでいいのかな？言い方。
Uh, is 'Oden Soup Cabbage Roll' the right way to say it?
熱っ！おお。
Hot! Oh.
これを、果たして本当に美味いのかという…
We're wondering if this is actually delicious...
でも売ってるよね、結構。
But they do sell them quite often, right?
需要があったので、ちょっと食べてみますか。
Since there was demand, shall we try eating it?
食べてみますか！
Let's try eating it!
まつり先輩が…あ、箸！
Matsuri-senpai... Ah, chopsticks!
あ、マジでごめんなさい、体打っちゃって。
Ah, I'm seriously sorry, I bumped into you.
二人で食べるとしたら１、２個…
If two people are eating, one or two pieces...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、ありがとうございます。じゃあちょっと、ドリンクは？
Yes, thank you. So, how about drinks?
あ、水がね、自分であります。
Ah, for water, it's self-service.
ここで…水飲める…
Here... you can drink water...
確かに。まつり先輩に…
True. To Matsuri-senpai...
コンソメはね…おでん出汁ロールキャベツ…
The consomme is... Oden soup cabbage roll...
お腹結構いっぱい…ねあ。
My stomach is pretty full... yeah.
みんな少食だな。
Everyone has such small appetites.
まつり先輩、マジで無限に食べてくれるからな。
Matsuri-senpai seriously eats an infinite amount for us.
困ったらまつり先輩呼べばなんとかなるんですよね。
If we're in trouble, we can just call Matsuri-senpai and it'll work out.
呼んで！飛んでくるし。
Call her! She'll fly right over.
そう、飛んできてくれるし。飛んでくる。
Yeah, she'll fly over for us. She'll fly over.
なんか食べ物…あるのかな？
Is there... any food?
来たー！イエーイ！
They're here! Yay!
なんか食べ物あるのかな？ヤア！バウバウ！
Is there any food here? Yah! Bau bau!
おでん、おでん。唐揚げもある！
We have oden, oden. There's also karaage!
最高！
Awesome!
もう、いっぱい食べます！
We're going to eat a lot!
うん！着けた！
Yeah! We made it!
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
わざわざ我はカオス、終わりの果て、ジ・エンド、氷の理不尽、砕かれしバラ、汝の友、ホロ伊への箱、ハコス・ベールズです！
I am Chaos, the end of the end, The End, the icy absurdity, the shattered rose, thy friend, Holo-E's box... I am Hakos Baelz!
イェーイ！おったー！
Yay! She's here!
本物のやつ達来たー！
The real ones are here!
お邪魔します。いる？
Excuse us. Need some?
食べる…一個。一個でいいの？
I'll eat... one. Is one enough?
じゃあ…ま、おでんもあるわ。
Well... we have oden too.
おでんも！あ、ありがとう！
Oden too! Ah, thank you!
ドリンクは？
How about drinks?
おでんおでんキュンもしますよ。
We'll do 'Oden Oden Kyun' too.
おでんおでんキュン！
Oden Oden Kyun!
レギュラーメニュー化したのか。
Has that become a regular menu item?
マジか…いいのか。そういう店だった？
Seriously... is that okay? Was this that kind of shop?
あの今回、こちらにですね、ちょっとこの格好のところに物が少ないんで、あと発掘するのが大変だったりするんですけど…
This time, over here, the pot is a bit empty, and it's hard to excavate the food, but...
おでんのお品書きがありますので。
We have an oden menu here.
食べたいやつをフワモコちゃんに言うと、頑張って取ってくれます。
If you tell FuwaMoco what you want, they'll do their best to get it.
あー！お給仕係フワモコちゃん！
Ah! FuwaMoco are the servers!
ニャー！はいはいはい！はいはいはい！
Meow! Yes yes yes! Yes yes yes!
えー！
Eeeh!
え、え、僕は、大根！
Uh, uh, I want daikon!
大根！オッケー！
Daikon! Okay!
たまご！
Egg!
たまご！オッケー！ちくわ！
Egg! Okay! Chikuwa!
ちくわ、オッケー！ちくわ！
Chikuwa, okay! Chikuwa!
ダブルちくわ！これ！
Double Chikuwa! This one!
ちくわ！トリプル！
Chikuwa! Triple!
トリプルちくわ！ちくわ好きだ！
Triple Chikuwa! You love chikuwa!
そんなに食べれる？
Can you eat that much?
ちくわ大好き！ちくわ大好きだ！
I love chikuwa! I love chikuwa!
たまごも！ウィー・ちくわ！
Egg too! We... Chikuwa!
じゃあ、お願いします！
Then, please!
オッケー！えっと、たまごな。
Okay! Um, egg.
それ、はんぺん。
That's hanpen.
たまご…ちくわ頼んだかな？
Egg... did we order chikuwa?
モコちゃん聞いてなかったの？え？
Moco-chan, you weren't listening? Eh?
たまご！たまごは…ちょっと待って。
Egg! Egg is... wait a minute.
どこ？ちょっと待って。
Where? Wait a minute.
たまごは…あ、たまごは…たまご。
Egg is... ah, egg is... egg.
最高すぎる。
This is too awesome.
あ、良かった。
Ah, that's good.
ありがとう！いらっしゃいませ！
Thank you! Welcome!
いつもご飯の時聞いてくれて…
You always ask us during meal times...
彼方につれて…いやいやいや。
Taken to Kanata... no no no.
大体来てくれる勢で、ご飯食べたい。
Usually, the group that comes wants to eat.
あ、そう！めっちゃ来たんだけどさ、もうヤバ！
Oh right! You came a lot, it was crazy!
ね、スケジュールヤバって言って、お互いにね、そうなんですよね。
Yeah, saying the schedule is crazy, for both of us, it really is.
で、今回来て、本当に良かった！
So, I'm really glad you came this time!
ちょうどね…良かった！
Just right... I'm glad!
楽しくて良かった！
I'm glad it was fun!
今日はいっぱい食べてってくれ！
Please eat a lot today!
食べる！梅ちゃんのお茶ね。
I'll eat! That's Ume-chan's tea, right.
可愛い！ちょっと！ヤバイ！これ。
Cute! Wait! This is dangerous!
なんか違う店始まってるか？
Has a different kind of shop opened?
違う店始まっとる！
A different shop has opened!
はい！ちょっと待ってこれ…ヤバイ。
Yes! Wait a minute, this is... dangerous.
絶対見せれない中入ってるから。
We absolutely can't show what's inside.
いや、これ急速で飲むから、後で。
No, I'll drink this rapidly later.
じゃあちょっとね、ここカメラエリアなんで気を付けて。
Well, this is the camera area, so be careful.
じゃあこれが、便利な、たまご、ちくわ、こんにゃく、大根が入ってます。
So this has the convenient egg, chikuwa, konjac, and daikon.
じゃあ…ありがとう、ありがとうございます。
Here... thanks, thank you very much.
はーい！おでんおでんキュンは要りますか？
Okay! Do you need the 'Oden Oden Kyun'?
あ、おでん美味しくする…
Ah, to make the oden delicious...
おでんおでんキュン！
Oden Oden Kyun!
ヤベ、忘れてた。
Crap, I forgot.
オッケー！オッケー！
Okay! Okay!
キュン！
Kyun!
はい！
Yes!
おでん！美味しくなーれ！
Oden! Become delicious!
おでん！おでんキューン！
Oden! Oden Kyuuun!
かわ…はんぺん！はんぺん！
Cu... Hanpen! Hanpen!
はんぺん！あれ？
Hanpen! Huh?
こっちはんぺん。ハートじゃなくてはんぺん？
This is hanpen. Not a heart, but hanpen?
はんぺんね！可愛い！
Hanpen, huh! Cute!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
うー、食べてー！
Ooh, eat up!
いただきまーす！
Itadakimasu!
おおーっ！
Ooh!
ちょっと見せないといけない。
I have to show this.
結構な量のお茶入れちゃった。
I poured quite a lot of tea.
ゆっくり…
Slowly...
急速で任せろ。
Leave it to me, I'll be quick.
あずいろ食堂…開店！
Azuiro Diner... Open!
あずきちゃんと、かざま。
AZKi-chan and Kazama.
おおー！
Ooh!
これ見せますね。
I'll show this to you.
無理させちゃった。
We made you push yourself.
きゅーと！
Cute!
かわいい！
So cute!
かわいいー！
Cute!
絵、上手！
You're good at drawing!
分かりやすいように書いたよ。
I drew it so it's easy to understand.
大事なお茶を…
The precious tea...
ごめん！
Sorry!
なんで！？
Why!?
お茶いっぱい入れちゃった。
I poured too much tea.
ゆっくり食べてください。
Please eat slowly.
FWMCもね…
FWMC is also...
そうですよね。
That's right.
ごはん大好き。
We love food.
大好き。
Love it.
いつも美味しいって食べてくれる、作ったもの。
They always eat what I make saying it's delicious.
何でも食べますよ。
We'll eat anything.
食べてきます。
We'll eat it all.
好き嫌いとかないですか？
Do you have any likes or dislikes?
ない！
None!
ええーすごい！
Ehh, amazing!
アレルギー以外はない。
Nothing except allergies.
えーすごい！
Wow, amazing!
えらーい！
Good girls!
確かに、いつも何出しても大体何でも食べてくれる。
True, they usually eat whatever I serve.
好き嫌いないなぁ。
No likes or dislikes, huh.
偉いぞ！
Admirable!
えっ嘘？
Eh, really?
食べるんだ。
You eat it.
食べる。
We eat.
おでん、ロールキャベツありか？全然。
Is Cabbage Roll in Oden okay? Totally?
待ち。
Wait.
うん？
Hm?
卵の黄身めっちゃでかいんだけど！
The egg yolk is super huge!
えーっ！？
Ehhh!?
当たりー！
Jackpot!
でも確かに、大きい！
But it's true, it is big!
美味しい！
Delicious!
大きい！
Big!
双子？こんなに大きいの？
Twins? Is it really this big?
当たりかも。
Might be a winner.
いつもなんかグリーンになっちゃうですね。
It always turns green, doesn't it.
すげえ！
Whoa!
ちょっとこれ、見せていい？
Can I show this a bit?
めっちゃ大きい！
It's super big!
ちょっと大きすぎて…
It's a bit too big...
でかいな！
It's huge!
でかい！
Huge!
わあー！
Wow!
みんなに見せたい。
I want to show everyone.
でかいぐらいでかい。
It's huge-level huge.
大きな黄身！
Big yolk!
えっ！？
Eh!?
でか！
Huge!
でかすぎる！
Too huge!
当たりだ！
It's a winner!
当たりー！
Jackpot!
当たりだー！
It's a jackpot!
いや、すごいな。
Wow, that's amazing.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
よし、食べます。
Alright, I'll eat.
食べてください。
Please eat.
いただきます！
Let's eat!
ロールキャベツおでん。
Cabbage Roll Oden.
ありです、これ。
This is totally legit.
おーっ。
Ooh.
この出汁でさ、なんか…
With this dashi, it's kind of...
なんだ、なんか調和されてるぞ。
It's harmonized or something.
え、ロールキャベツ普通おでんに入らないですか？
Eh, does Cabbage Roll not usually go in Oden?
あんまり入らない。
Not usually.
めっちゃ合うよ！
It matches so well!
確かに。
True.
ロールキャベツは、ないということが…
Cabbage Rolls being missing is...
お店とかだとちょいちょいあるけど、
Shops have it sometimes, but...
やっぱ家だと面倒くさいし、ロールキャベツはね。
At home it's a hassle, Cabbage Rolls.
いや、稀なんですよね、ロールキャベツね。
It's rare, Cabbage Rolls are.
変わり種だね。
It's a unique item.
頑張りましたから、あずきさんは。
AZKi-san worked hard on it.
かーっ！
Kaa!
もう最高すぎる。
It's just too awesome.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうです！
Thank you!
はぁ、幸せだな。
Ah, I'm happy.
うまい。
Tasty.
いや、美味しい。
Man, it's good.
あー、よかった。
Ah, I'm glad.
FWMCちゃん、お仕事してたの？
Were you working, Fuwamoco-chan?
うん！
Yeah!
えらーい！
Good girls!
なんか、いっぱいやってるね。
Like, doing a lot of stuff.
最近はね、みんな…
Recently, everyone...
やっぱフェスの準備とかね。
Like prepping for the Fes.
確かに。
True.
そうですね。
That's right.
そう、どうしても、みんな時間がなかなかなて、
Yeah, everyone just doesn't have much time,
大変な中、今日はありがとうございます。
so thank you for coming today amidst the busyness.
いやもう…
No no...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
これでも来ますよ、これがあるなら。
We'd come anyway if you have this.
これがあるならば。
If you have this.
マジで早いからな、待ち時間。
Because the wait time is seriously fast.
うん。
Yeah.
嬉しい！
I'm happy!
は、8時から開けてたんですか？
Wha- were you open since 8?
えっとね、8時から開けて…そう！
Umm, opened since 8... yes!
ただやっぱ、確かに今日マネちゃんとかにスケジュールを聞いた感じも、
But asking Mane-chan about the schedule today,
みんな大体このぐらいの時間にやっぱお仕事が終わったりとか、
it seemed everyone finishes work around this time,
ああー。
Aah.
そうだったりとか。
or something like that.
はいはいはい。
Yes yes yes.
そう。
Yeah.
みんな大変。
Everyone's busy.
だからお腹空かせて来る人、愛おしいって感じで。
So people who come hungry are just adorable.
いや、お腹空いた！
Man, we were hungry!
すごい！
Amazing!
モコちゃん先輩、いつもお腹空かせて来る。
Moco-chan-senpai always comes hungry.
うん！
Yeah!
今日も何も食べずに来たもんね。
Came without eating anything today too, right.
えらい！
Good girl!
あー、何も食べずに来たの？
Ah, you came without eating anything?
あー！
Ah!
ちゃんとご飯食いつまた！
We ate properly!
ねえ、おにぎり持ち帰ってもいい？一個。
Hey, can I take an Onigiri home? One.
いいですよ。
Sure.
ふわもこ、おにぎり食べた？
Fuwamoco, did you eat Onigiri?
ねえ、美味しかった！
Yeah, it was delicious!
梅干し食べたことない。
Never ate Umeboshi (pickled plum).
ええっ！？
Ehhh!?
なんで！？
Why!?
梅干しを食べたことない！？
You've never eaten Umeboshi!?
え？
Eh?
は？
Hah?
ない！
Never!
No!
なんで？
Why?
おにぎり、鮭とツナマヨしか食べたことない。
For Onigiri, only ever ate Salmon and Tuna Mayo.
えーっ！？
Ehhh!?
え、弁当に乗ってたりするじゃん。
Eh, it's usually on top of bento boxes though.
食べたことない。
Never ate it.
おい！えー！？
Oi! Ehhh!?
噂で酸っぱいと言うからね。
Because rumors say it's sour.
あ、酸っぱいのが苦手？
Ah, you're bad with sour things?
じゃない。
Not that.
食べたことないから分かんない。
Never ate it so I don't know.
はっはっはっは！
Hahahaha!
え、酸っぱいものは好き？
Eh, do you like sour things?
酸っぱいものも食べたことない。
Never ate sour things either.
えっ！？
Ehhh!?
でもレモンは？
But what about lemons?
でもレモンは…
But lemons are...
アレルギーで食べれないし。
Allergic so can't eat them.
ええー！？
Ehhh!?
そっか！
I see!
レモンはダメなんだ！
Lemons are no good!
クエン酸？
Citric acid?
なんか柑橘類がダメだ。
Like citrus fruits are no good.
あ、柑橘類！
Ah, citrus!
柚子とか。
Like Yuzu.
はいはいはい。
Yes yes yes.
そうなんや。
Is that so.
昆布も…アレルギー？
Kelp too... is an allergy?
柑橘系とか…
Like citrus fruits...
クエ様はでも舐めれるよ。
But I can lick Lord Kue.
クエ様ね…
Lord Kue, huh...
クエ様…大丈夫。
Lord Kue... is okay.
え？どうなるんだろうね？
Eh? What would happen?
毒、毒の味がするわ、するけど。
It tastes like poison... well, it does.
おかかとか昆布もない。食べたこと。
No bonito flakes or kelp either. Never ate them.
え、何ですか？アレルギーとかじゃない？
Eh, what is it? Not an allergy?
じゃない。偏食。
No. Just picky eating.
すごー！
Wow!
赤だけを避けて通れば…
If I just avoid the red ones...
鮭とツナマヨだけで生きてきた。
I've lived on only salmon and tuna mayo.
絶対どっかで出会う。
You'll definitely encounter them somewhere.
チョコミントも食べたことないよ。
I haven't eaten Choco Mint either.
チョコは食べなくていい。
You don't need to eat the chocolate.
チョコミント…本当に怒られるよ！
Choco Mint... You'll really get scolded!
チョコミント民に。
By the Choco Mint people.
チョコミントいるぞ、多分。
Choco Mint (fans) are here, probably.
チョコミントよりミントの方が好き。
I like mint better than Choco Mint.
チョコなくてもいいわね。
Don't really need the chocolate, huh.
そう！それぞれ邪魔。
Right! They get in each other's way.
混ぜる必要ないよね。
No need to mix them, right?
ミントだけで美味しい。
It's delicious with just mint.
チョコだけでいいし、ミントだけでいいし。
Just chocolate is fine, just mint is fine.
わざわざトゥースペーストにチョコ一緒に食わないじゃん？
You don't go out of your way to eat chocolate with toothpaste, right?
そうだよねー。
That's true~.
めっちゃわかる。
I totally get it.
トゥースペーストだけ食べたいよね。
You just want to eat the toothpaste.
いや、それはないね。
No, that's not it.
ヤバい、コメント欄の顔真っ赤っか。
Oh no, the faces in the comments are bright red.
顔真っ赤っかでワロタ。
Laughing at the bright red faces.
まあまあ、ちょっとね、チョコミントはね…
Now, now... you see, Choco Mint is...
あの何て言うかね、僕はね…
Umm, how should I put it, I...
ちょっと神の舌持ってるから、ちょっと凡人の舌は…
...possess a God Tongue, so the tongues of commoners...
ちょっと理解できないっていうかね。
...can't really understand it, you know.
敵に回そうとしてる？
Are you trying to make enemies?
色かわいいけどね。
The color is cute though.
BAU BAU!
ヤッホー！
Yap-ho!
今日もかわいいね！
You're cute today too!
ヤバい、今炎上中。
Oh no, currently flaming.
そう、今炎上してる、姉ちゃんが。
Yeah, big sis is currently flaming.
すいません。チョコミント美味しくないって言って炎上した。
Sorry. Flamed for saying Choco Mint isn't delicious.
あ、育ってもいい？
Ah, can I nurture it?
いいよ！
Sure!
ごめんね、どっち？
Sorry, which one?
みんなの隣に…
Next to everyone...
大丈夫です。
It's okay.
唐揚げ食べる？
Will you eat fried chicken?
え、食べる！
Eh, I'll eat it!
おでんも。
Oden too.
おでん！
Oden!
来てくださったのは…
The ones who came are...
じゃあ、自己紹介します！
Then, we'll introduce ourselves!
自己紹介！忘れてた！
Self-intro! I forgot!
マイクはどこにある？
Where is the mic?
頭の上？
Above the head?
え？あ、ここ？
Eh? Ah, here?
Mococo Abyssgard to Hololive English -Advent-!
Fuwawa Abyssgard desu!
FUWAMOCO desu!
We are FUWAMOCO!
BAU BAU!
おでんいっぱい食べると温まるよ。
You'll warm up if you eat lots of Oden.
唐揚げ1個で…温かい唐揚げ食べたーい。
One fried chicken... I want warm fried chicken.
温かい唐揚げ食べてね！
Eat some warm fried chicken!
最高！
Awesome!
おでん食べたことあるんだ？
Have you eaten Oden before?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
覚えてない。
Don't remember.
ないかも。
Maybe never.
初めて！？
First time!?
ファーストおでん来た！
First Oden is here!
え、おでん？おでん？
Eh, Oden? Oden?
カモン！
Come on!
あ、メニューがあるんだ。
Ah, there is a menu.
たまごあるかな？まだ。
Is there egg? Still?
たまごもしかしてある気配。
Signs of egg potentially existing.
温かい方が美味しいよね、赤ちゃんでもね。
Warm is better, right? Even for babies.
え、ちくわぶ…ちくわぶ。
Eh, Chikuwabu... Chikuwabu.
おでん…ちくわ？
Oden... Chikuwa?
ちくわぶっていう生き物は、丸々になってる？
Is the creature called Chikuwabu completely round?
その方がかわいいからね。
Because it's cuter that way.
ネズミっていう生き物は…
The creature called a mouse...
かわいい！
Cute!
絶対美味しい！
Definitely delicious!
丸、丸々。
Round, roundly.
えっと、みんなは大根、こんにゃく…
Um, everyone wants Daikon, Konnyaku...
ちくわ、あと何だっけ？
Chikuwa, and what else?
よしじゃあ、大根、こんにゃく、ちくわー！
Alright then, Daikon, Konnyaku, Chikuwa!
あとサツマイモを入れてあげてください。
Also please put in sweet potato.
ちくわ知らない？
You don't know Chikuwa?
フィッシュケーキ。
Fish cake.
大根！
Daikon!
フィッシュケーキなら知ってる！
I know it if it's fish cake!
ENのIDが来てくれるとこれがあるから面白い。
It's funny when EN/ID members come because this happens.
面白いね。
It's funny, right?
あのネズミの代わりでいいですか？
Is this okay as a substitute for the mouse?
ありますよ！もちろんあります！
We have it! Of course we have it!
あ、それは…紅茶？
Ah, is that... black tea?
さつま揚げとか、はんぺんとか多分ある。
There's probably fried fish cake and hanpen.
ちくわ、ちくわ、ちくわ…
Chikuwa, chikuwa, chikuwa...
ちくわまだあるよ。
There's still chikuwa left.
やったー！
Yay!
たまご！
Eggs!
あ、たまごもうないかも。
Ah, there might be no more eggs.
たまご売り切れ。
Eggs are sold out.
売り切れ！？
Sold out?!
たまご売り切れ。
Eggs are sold out.
売り切れ…
Sold out...
あ、最後取っちゃった…
Ah, I took the last one...
あ、ごめん。
Ah, sorry.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
あ、ごめん。
Ah, sorry.
でかい大当たり。
The big jackpot.
でかい大当たり、はんぺん。
The big jackpot, hanpen.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
あたり、はんぺん。
Jackpot hanpen.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
え、食べちゃう？
Eh, you gonna eat it?
食べる！
I'll eat it!
あ、いいよ、食べて。
Ah, sure, go ahead.
あんむ！
Nom!
おお、すごい！
Oh, amazing!
たまごない…
No eggs...
すごいよね。
It's amazing, right?
おいしい！
Delicious!
贅沢ちゃん。
Little luxury.
の、愛。
Of... love.
おいしい！
Yummy!
そうだね。
That's right.
フワモコのおすすめで詰めてみました。
I packed it with FUWAMOCO's recommendations.
はんぺんとこんにゃく、大根…
Hanpen, konnyaku, radish...
あとは練り物系が…
And the fish paste items...
いろいろいっぱい入ってます。
There's a lot of different things inside.
やー！温かいから…
Yay! Since it's hot...
こっち、こっち。
Here, here.
おでんはドリンク？
Is oden a drink?
まあ、大事。
Well, important.
おでんはドリンク！
Oden is a drink!
あ、そうだ、大事だった。
Oh right, it was important.
おいしくなーれ！
Oishiku-nare! (Become delicious!)
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
行きますよー！
Here we go!
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, Oden, Kyun!
きゅーん！
Kyun!
バウバウ！
BAU BAU!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
一番美味しかった。
It was the most delicious.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
はんぺん天才。
Hanpen is genius.
はんぺんの形だ。
It's the shape of Hanpen.
はんぺんすごいふわふわでおいしかった。
The hanpen was so fluffy and delicious.
おでんきゅん、今日の笑顔になる。
Oden-Kyun puts a smile on today's face.
はんぺんだそうで、おいしいはんぺん。
They say it's hanpen, delicious hanpen.
はんぺんうまいよね！
Hanpen is good, isn't it!
おい、大丈夫ですか？
Oi, are you okay?
あ、大丈夫だね。
Ah, they're okay.
オッケー。
Okay.
昆布とかも…
Kelp is also...
おいしいよ、おいしいよ。
It's tasty, it's tasty.
昆布おいしいから。
Because kelp is delicious.
昆布食べる？
Want to eat kelp?
あ、昆布食べていいよ。
Ah, you can eat the kelp.
わあ、おいしかったから！
Wow, since it was delicious!
普通は食べないけど、健康にいいよね。
I don't usually eat it, but it's healthy.
食べる、食べる。
I'll eat it, I'll eat it.
増える。
Increasing.
あ、来た！
Ah, it's here!
お待たせいたしました！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, Oden, Kyun!
バウバウ！おでんきゅんしたから。
Bau bau! Since we did Oden-Kyun.
いい匂い！
Smells good!
どうぞ、どうぞ。
Go ahead, go ahead.
おかわり？
Seconds?
たまごもうないかも。
Eggs might be gone.
普通に晩御飯食べに来た。
Just came to eat dinner normally.
具材がほぼなくなってる。
The ingredients are almost gone.
すごい！
Wow!
やばい、幸せすぎる。
Oh my, too happy.
幸せ。
Happiness.
あの無限の鍋だったのに。
It was supposed to be an infinite pot.
あれ？
Huh?
なんかこぼしちゃった。
I spilled something.
あ、ごめん。
Ah, sorry.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
いいよ、昆布食べる？
It's fine, want to eat kelp?
昆布おいしかった。
Kelp was delicious.
フワ、昆布あんまり好きじゃないけどおいしかった。
Fuwa doesn't like kelp much, but it was delicious.
ね、良かった。
Right? That's good.
え、こんにゃくも食べたいけど、大丈夫？
Eh, I want to eat konnyaku too, is that okay?
ね、まだ食べてないよね、こっちある。
Yeah, haven't eaten it yet, it's over here.
ロールキャベツ入ってます。
There are cabbage rolls inside.
ロールキャベツ初めて？
First time for cabbage rolls?
えっとね…
Umm...
キャベツの中に…
Inside the cabbage...
牛肉と豚肉の…合い挽き…
Beef and pork... minced mixture...
ハンバーグみたいな。
It's like a hamburger steak.
かわいい！
Cute!
これ、一緒にミックス…
This, mixed together...
出たの？
It came out?
なるほど！
I see!
え、ありがとう。
Eh, thank you.
かわいい！
Cute!
ロールキャベツ、初めて？
First time for cabbage rolls?
え、初めてかも！
Eh, might be the first time!
作ったことない、作ったことない。
Never made it, never made it.
よく考えよう、ロールキャベツは…
Come to think of it, cabbage rolls...
作るのは大変なんだ。
Are hard to make.
どう？
How is it?
中に肉がいっぱい入ってる。
There's lots of meat inside.
おお、踊ってる！
Oh, it's dancing!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
踊ってる、踊ってる。
Dancing, dancing.
食感がうまい！
The texture is good!
写真撮ろう。
Let's take a picture.
あれ？ロールキャベツ初！
Huh? First cabbage roll!
ねえちゃん食べてください。
Sister, please eat it.
ああ、嬉しい。
Ah, happy.
でもこれ、あれ？これは…あっちにあったやつ？
But this, huh? Was this... the one over there?
そう、それコンソメ味。
Yes, that's consomme flavor.
コンソメ味！
Consomme flavor!
一応ね、おでんの中にも入ってます。
Actually, it's also inside the oden.
おでんの出汁のパターンと、そのコンソメの出汁のパターン。
The oden soup stock pattern, and the consomme stock pattern.
ロールキャベツ、いろいろあるんだ。
There are various types of cabbage rolls.
トマトもあるもんね。
There's tomato too.
そう、我々はよく作るのがトマト味っていうので一致してたけど…
Right, we agreed that we usually make the tomato flavor, but...
今日はね、コンソメと、新たな…
Today, it's consomme, and a new...
新たな味。
New flavor.
うー、無害！
Ooh, harmless! (Misheard 'Umai' as 'Mugai'?)
ロールキャベツ、食べたことないかも。
Might have never eaten cabbage rolls.
あ、食べる？
Ah, want to eat?
食べる！
I'll eat!
一個あるよ、ここ。
There's one here.
あ、これ半分こしたら？
Ah, why not split this one?
普通の食べるか、おでんの食べるか、どっちにする？
Eat the regular one, or the oden one, which one?
あ、こっちの！
Ah, this one!
大丈夫か？！
Are you sure?!
普通のトマト…
Normal tomato...
知らねえよ！
I don't know!
あ、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay okay.
大丈夫か？
You okay?
おでんにする？
Go with oden?
おでんの出汁…
Oden soup stock...
コンソメもあるよ、コンソメ。
There's consomme too, consomme.
あ、今の、おでんにします！
Ah, I'll have the oden one now!
あ、おでんキャベツ。
Ah, oden cabbage.
僕の前で、ボウル三つあるんじゃ。
There are three bowls in front of me.
取ってちゃん。
Totte-chan. (Taking it?)
本当にだ！
It's true!
ビュッフェ、ビュッフェ！
Buffet, buffet!
ビュッフェだ、もう。僕の前で、ボウル三つがあります。
It's a buffet. There are three bowls in front of me.
大砲だ！
It's a cannon!
おでん食べ放題！
All-you-can-eat oden!
やった！
Yay!
うめえ、余裕っす！
Yummy, easy peasy!
最高すぎる。
Too awesome.
どうですか？
How is it?
おいしい！
Delicious!
やったー！
Yay!
すごいジューシー！
So juicy!
温かいがありますか？
Is there warmth?
手間の分…
The effort...
手間の分、報われた気がする。
I feel like the effort paid off.
全然耐えてないよ。
Not enduring at all.
And only egg 食べたことある。
And I've only eaten egg before.
Morning Cabbage.
モーニングキャベツ？
Morning Cabbage?
It happens, it happens.
いや、おいしい。
No, it's delicious.
出た、出た！
It came out, it came out!
どう、おでん？
How is the oden?
めっちゃおいしい！
Very delicious!
はーい！
Yess!
好きな具材、どれがおいしかったとかね。
Which favorite ingredient was tasty?
教えてください。
Please tell me.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
はんぺん美味しい！
Hanpen is delicious!
はんぺんか…美味しいかな？
Hanpen, huh... Is it good?
はんぺん美味しいよ！
Hanpen is yummy!
はんぺんてさ、そもそもどういう味だっけ？
Wait, what does Hanpen actually taste like again?
はんぺんね…
Hanpen is...
魚のすり身の…大人気だ。
It's fish paste... It's really popular.
曖昧だ…味がわからん。
That's vague... I don't know the taste.
食感がいいのかな？
Maybe it's the texture?
食感なのかな？味？
Is it texture? Or taste?
うーん、なんかよくわからないかも。
Hmm, I might not really know.
ふわふわ！
It's fluffy!
多分、はんぺんの食感は、なんか塩っぱいマシュマロみたい？
I think Hanpen's texture is... like a salty marshmallow?
マシュマロか！
Marshmallow, huh!
あの皮がないから、マシュマロか。
Since it doesn't have skin... yeah, marshmallow.
モコちゃんの例えがめちゃくちゃ的確かも。
Moco-chan's metaphor might be incredibly accurate.
的確だもん！
It is accurate!
食べるよ！
I'm eating!
あーんしてる。
She's doing 'Aan'.
あーんしてる！
She's doing 'Aan'!
She's waiting to be fed!
おじさんレーダー早いですよ！
The 'Old Man Radar' is picking up fast!
いや、わかるよ！
No, I get it!
やましいことじゃないから！
It's nothing sketchy!
コンニャク美味しい。
Konjac is yummy.
凝視しそうになったら抑えたんですから。
Because I stopped myself when I almost started staring.
抑えたんですか？
You held back?
もう一回見れるかな？
Can I see it one more time?
あーん！
Aan!
ここにおじさんレーダー…
The Old Man Radar here is...
おじさんレーダー、ずっと今日戦ってるんだよ、ずっと風真は。
The Old Man Radar... I've been fighting it all day today.
おじさんレーダー…いや、フワモコはね…
Old Man Radar... well, Fuwamoco is...
だって、おじさんレーダーをくすぐるものがいっぱいあるもんね。
I mean, there are so many things that tickle the Old Man Radar.
いっぱいあるもんね。
There really are.
はああー！
Haaaa!
そう、尻尾と耳を…
Yes, the tails and ears...
いつ、モフっていいのかと…
Wondering when I can fluff them...
ずっと我慢してる！
I've been holding back the whole time!
あー、モフれない！
Ah, can't fluff them!
DON'T TOUCH！
DON'T TOUCH!
DON'T TOUCH って言われちゃうからね！
Since I'll get told 'DON'T TOUCH'!
まだ嫌われたくない！
I don't want to be hated yet!
まだ嫌われたくないんだ！
I really don't want to be hated yet!
唐揚げ…うん。
Karaage... yeah.
動くの？
It moves?
これね、取り分けるよ。
I'll serve this up.
取り分け用のお皿…
A plate for serving...
え、で、フワモコペアで…？
Eh, so, the Fuwamoco pair is...
何個食べる？
How many do you want?
本当は尻尾、モフりたい！
I really want to fluff the tails!
NO MORE！
NO MORE!
触っちゃうから、今日は出来ない！
I'd end up touching, so I can't today!
今日は…今日は人のチャンネルだし、自粛してるんだ！
Today... since it's someone else's channel, I'm restraining myself!
あ、それね、取り分け用の箸だから。
Ah, those are the serving chopsticks.
あ、間違えた！
Ah, my mistake!
食べたい！
I want to eat!
危ない危ない危ない！
Watch out, watch out, watch out!
逃げないで！
Don't run away!
うわぁ、最高の景色だー！
Wow, this is the best scenery!
うまい飯を食べながら…
Eating delicious food while...
うめぇ飯食べながら…
While eating yummy food...
可愛い子を眺める！
Gazing at cute girls!
ここ一番…
This is where...
一番なんか、おじさんが出てた。
The 'Old Man' came out the most just now.
最高の景色だ！
It's the best scenery!
最高の景色だ…！
It's the best scenery...!
すごい、おじさんしかいない。
Wow, there's only an old man here.
美味しいな。
It's delicious.
おっさんいます、すいません。
There's an old man here, sorry.
パワー増すなぁ。
My power is increasing.
お腹いっぱい？
Are you full?
お腹いっぱい！
I'm full!
いっぱい？
Full?
ねぇねぇ風真、今日はお土産のクッキーはないの？
Hey hey Kazama, are there no souvenir cookies today?
今日はね、みんなでつまんでもらおうと思って…
Today, I thought we could all snack on them...
だけどそこに袋があるでしょ？
But there's a bag right there, see?
あ、そこに袋がある！
Ah, there is a bag there!
ここに！
Right here!
ちなみに、あの控え室になんかいい感じの…
By the way, in the waiting room, there was some nice...
プラバック…お弁当箱みたいなのがあって。
Plastic box... like a lunch box.
唐揚げ美味しかった！
The fried chicken was delicious!
いつの間に！？
When did you eat it!?
本当です！おおおー！
It's true! Whoa!
減った！？
It decreased!?
危ない危ない！
Watch out, watch out!
お疲れ様です！
Good work!
いい意味で！
In a good way!
落ちちゃうよ！
You're gonna fall!
じゃあ、自己紹介お願いしますか？
Well then, shall we do the self-introduction?
はい！
Yes!
せーの！
Ready!
うーん、バウバウ！
Uun, BAU BAU!
やったー！
Yay!
今日のキラキラな、ビビです！
We are today's sparkly, Bibi!
こんばんは！
Good evening!
久々！
Long time no see!
お久しぶりです！
It's been a while!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
みんな生きてる？
Is everyone alive?
髪ボールがすごい似合うね、とっても、いいですか？
That hairball suits you, can I take it?
え、すごい美味しそうな匂い！
Eh, it smells super delicious!
もぐもぐしてる！
She's chewing!
やったー！
Yay!
お腹空いてきました！
I'm getting hungry!
じゃあ今日は、いっぱいおでんがあります。
Well then, we have lots of Oden today.
そうです、品切れ。
Yes, but some are sold out.
ただ、卵が品切れになりました！
However, we are out of eggs!
あ、残念！
Ah, that's too bad!
残念…食べちゃった？
Too bad... did you eat them?
すいません！
Sorry!
食べちゃった？
You ate them?
すいません！
I'm sorry!
食べちゃった！
She ate them!
ま、ここにね、おでんの具の…ここちょっとカメラがあるんで気をつけてもらって。
Well, right here, the Oden ingredients... there's a camera here so please be careful.
ちょっと少ないけど、ロールキャベツとかおでんのやつまだあります。
It's running a bit low, but we still have cabbage rolls and other Oden stuff.
食べたいやつ言ってもらうと…
If you tell us what you want to eat...
ちょっと、ポンコツちゃんが、まだおでんの名前と見た目が…
Our little clumsy one here hasn't quite matched the names and looks yet...
完全に一致してないんですけど、頑張って注いでくれるんで。
They don't match completely, but she'll do her best to serve you.
修行中だ！
I'm in training!
じゃあ、ビビ、餅巾着！
Okay then, Bibi wants a Mochi Kinchaku!
餅巾着！？
Mochi Kinchaku!?
あれ、売り切れかも？
Oh, that might be sold out?
売り切れたかも、ごめん！
Might be sold out, sorry!
大根とか…
Radish or...
お腹減らしてきたのに！
Even though we came hungry!
じゃあ、コンニャクありますか？
Then, do you have Konjac?
コンニャクあります！
We have Konjac!
コンニャクと…
Konjac and...
じゃあ、せっかくなのでロールキャベツを。
Then, since we're here, a Cabbage Roll.
ロールキャベツ、はい！
Cabbage Roll, yes!
乾杯、乾杯！
Cheers, cheers!
乾杯してます。
They are toasting.
はんぺんオススメだよ！
Hanpen is recommended!
あ、はんぺん！
Ah, Hanpen!
すごい美味しい
It's super delicious!
食べたことない？
Have you never eaten it?
自ら選ばないかも
I might not choose it myself.
FUWAMOCOだってはんぺん食べたことあった
Even FUWAMOCO has eaten hanpen before.
え、うそー！待ってくださいよ
Eh, no way! Wait a minute.
あとね、昆布とか完食…
Also, the kelp and such... finish eating...
完食絶対完食
Finish eating, definitely finish eating.
昆布？
Kelp?
昆布美味しいよ
Kelp is yummy.
昆布も食べたことないかも、おでんの
I might not have eaten oden kelp either.
えー！うそ！
Eeh! No way!
ここでじゃあ挑戦します
Then I'll try it here.
挑戦ですよ！
It's a challenge!
そうなんだー
Is that so?
なんかうち食堂なんですけど
This is a diner, though...
なんかあの、メイド喫茶みたいな過剰なサービスが
There's this excessive service like a maid cafe...
楽しい～
This is fun~
お金取られないですか？
You won't take our money, right?
取らない、じゃあちょっとやっていただきました
Won't take it. We just had you do it a bit.
じゃああの二人に
So, for those two...
お正月…
New Year's...
全部健康は良くっていただいて
Take in all the healthiness...
はい！
Yes!
元気作って
Build up energy...
行きますよ～
Here we go~
一週間分！
One week's worth!
注入！しゅー！
Injection! Shuu!
しゅー！
Shuu!
一週間…
One week...
ああー
Aah~
よかったー
Thank goodness.
あ席は向こうにあるんで
Ah, the seats are over there.
あと唐揚げとかクッキーとか
Also karaage, cookies...
おにぎりとか牛乳もあるんで
...rice balls, and milk are available.
あ、いただきます
Ah, let's eat.
やったー
Yay!
座る座る
Sit, sit.
座って
Sit down.
座る
I'll sit.
よーい時間でありがたいな
Grateful for the good timing.
いい匂いする
Smells good.
どうぞどうぞ
Go ahead, go ahead.
ビビが寄ってくるたびにもうめっちゃいい匂いする
Every time Bibi comes close, it smells super good.
え？
Eh?
おじさん！
Uncles!
おじさんしてないよ！
I'm not being an uncle!
食堂のおじさん
Diner uncle.
この店
This shop...
裏で働いてる厨房のおじさんと客のおじさんで
...is just a kitchen uncle in the back and a customer uncle.
いやちょっと、あの常連のおじさんだよ
No wait, I'm the regular customer uncle.
酒飲んでる？あず先輩
Are you drinking sake, AZ-senpai?
飲んでない！
I'm not drinking!
お疲れすぎてよ
You're just too tired!
まるで酔っ払いになってる
You're acting just like a drunkard.
いやでもあるんじゃないですか
But that happens, doesn't it?
たまに、なんか疲れがさ、溜まりすぎて
Sometimes, when tiredness builds up too much...
まるで酔ってる気分？
...you feel like you're drunk?
えー心配だよ休んでね
Eh, I'm worried. Please rest.
休みます
I will rest.
行ける？
Can you go on?
え、いただきます
Eh, let's eat.
おでんいただきます
I'll have the oden.
笑っちゃうんだけど
Makes me laugh.
嬉しい
I'm happy.
今日なんにも食べてなかったから
I hadn't eaten anything today.
みんななんにも食べてない
Everyone hasn't eaten anything.
ちょっと、こっちが心配なんですけど
Wait, we're the ones worried here.
みんなもっとちゃんと食べてくださいよ
Everyone please eat more properly.
え、じゃあFUWAMOCOちゃん
Eh, then FUWAMOCO-chan...
おすすめのほら、はんぺんをいただきます
...I'll have your recommended hanpen.
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
初はんぺん
First hanpen.
ん～！
Mmm!
柔らかい！
It's soft!
しみしみです
It's soaked in flavor.
出汁が効いてる
The dashi is working.
やっぱみんなはんぺん好きだね
Everyone likes hanpen after all.
はんぺん美味しい
Hanpen is yummy.
ね、はんぺん。まつり先輩が描いてくれた
Right, hanpen. Matsuri-senpai drew this.
ビビのイラスト
Illustration of Bibi.
あ、可愛い！
Ah, cute!
私ばかりが今日
Only I am...
お願いします
...please.
私子供色なんで
I'm in child mode.
いや良くないですよ
No, that's not good!
みんなもっとちゃんと食べてください
Everyone please eat more properly.
はーい
Okaay.
可愛い！
Cute!
イラストデータ、食堂にある
The illustration data is in the diner.
コップに分かりやすく貼ってある
Pasted clearly on the cup.
あ、ありがとうございます
Ah, thank you.
じゃあゼータちゃんのは
Then Zeta-chan's is...
ゼータちゃんのは
...Zeta-chan's is...
こんな感じです
...like this.
可愛い！
Cute!
わーキュート！
Waa, cute!
まつりが初めに描いた
Matsuri drew it first.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
可愛すぎる
Too cute.
間違いない
No doubt.
違うサービス始まってる
A different service has started.
いろんなサービスが
Various services...
ちゃんとしたサービスが
...proper services.
今日はありがとうございます
Thank you for today.
え、待って
Eh, wait.
あのデカすぎるタッパーに詰めてきた唐揚げなんか
That karaage packed in a huge tupperware...
空きが見える
...I can see some empty space.
だいぶ減ってる
It's decreased a lot.
食べて食べて
Eat, eat.
食べます
I'll eat.
任せろ
Leave it to me.
なんか入れ物もうない？
Any containers left?
すごい…向こうにある
Wow... over there.
もうなくなった？ひょっとして
Are they gone? Perhaps?
あ、こっちはね、これはクッキー入ってたやつだから
Ah, this one had cookies in it.
あとは多分こっちかな
Then maybe this one.
あ、あと二枚！
Ah, two more pieces!
白いやつ持ってきて
Bring the white one.
唐揚げ！
Karaage!
いいよあげる、あと全部食べていい
Sure, I'll give it. You can eat the rest.
唐揚げじゃあ貰います、このまま
Then I'll take the karaage, just like this.
めっちゃ食うじゃん
You eat a lot!
あ、これね、取り分けよう
Ah, let's share this.
はい
Yes.
お皿ある？
Is there a plate?
お皿ありますか？
Do you have a plate?
いい子
Good girl.
あ、あるから大丈夫
Ah, I have one so it's okay.
マネちゃんに
To Mane-chan...
マネちゃん！
Mane-chan!
白いの持っていって
Take the white one.
まこれも唐揚げ使ったんだけど
Well, this was used for karaage too.
あ、じゃあいいです
Ah, then it's fine.
いいよ
It's okay.
幸せだ
I'm happy.
幸せだー
So happy~
お弁当だと
If it's a bento...
唐揚げいただきます
I'll have the karaage.
はい、マネちゃん
Here, Mane-chan.
うわっ
Whoa.
あの白い
That white one...
デカい
...is big.
デカいね！
It's big, isn't it!
持ち帰りだね
Takeout.
持ち帰りよー！
Takeout!
はい
Yes.
もらた
Got it.
唐揚げやったー
Yay for karaage!
すごいね
Amazing.
なくなることってあるんだ、みんなって
I guess it does run out. Everyone...
お腹空いてるんだね
...is really hungry.
みんなお腹空いてねぇ
Everyone is hungry, huh.
お腹空いてね
Hungry.
ん〜！
Mmm!
おいひい、唐揚げおいひい！
Yummy, karaage is yummy!
やったー！
Yay!
ジューシー
Juicy.
こんなにカリカリに揚げるんや家で
To fry it this crispy at home...
お店みたいなカリカリさ
...it's crispy like a shop's.
ごちそうさまでした！
Thank you for the meal!
もう完食。
Already finished.
完食。いっぱい食べてくれた。
Finished. They ate so much.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
最高すぎる。
It's just the best.
まじで最高すぎる。
Seriously, it's the best.
デザートのクッキー。
And the dessert cookies.
あ、クッキー！
Ah, cookies!
クッキーまだありますんで。
We still have cookies.
そっちの状況見てないんですけど、
I wasn't watching the situation over there,
そっちの全部開けきりました？クッキー。
but did you open all of those cookies?
あのクッキー食べた？
Did you eat those cookies?
いや、でもまだここにあるのと...
No, but there's still some here and...
あとまつりが持って帰る。
And Matsuri will take the rest home.
持って帰る！持って帰る！
Taking them home! Taking them home!
おにぎりと...
The rice balls and...
おにぎりも持って帰ってくれる？
Will you take the rice balls home too?
初めて梅干し食べるかも。
This might be my first time eating umeboshi.
梅干し初めて！？
First time for umeboshi?!
梅干し...
Umeboshi...
FWちゃん食べたことある？
Have you eaten it before, FW-chan?
ある！
I have!
苦手な人は苦手ですよね、梅干し。
People who dislike it really dislike it, right?
です米。
That's true.
苦手？
Don't like it?
好き！
I like it!
あ、梅干し好きだった？
Ah, you liked umeboshi?
しゅき。
Love it.
じゃあ梅干し食べたことある？
So, have you eaten umeboshi?
ないかも。
Maybe not.
酸っぱいの食べれますか？
Can you eat sour things?
うん、食べれる。
Yeah, I can.
おにぎり美味しい。
The rice ball is tasty.
これ梅干し作っただって。
She said she made this umeboshi.
梅干しだけ？つけたやつ？
Just the umeboshi? The pickled one?
あの、作ったの、梅干し。
Um, I made it, the umeboshi.
自分で！？
By yourself!?
漬けた。
I pickled it.
すごい！美味しかったー！
Amazing! It was delicious!
じゃ一個もらっていいですか？
Can I have one?
あ、明日の朝ごはん？
Ah, for tomorrow's breakfast?
クッキーもらってもいいですか？
Can I have a cookie too?
もちろんもちろん！
Of course, of course!
え、最高。
Eh, this is the best.
もちろんって言って、まつりのじゃ...
I said 'of course', but they're Matsuri's...
テーブルを動かしてくれている方、任せた！
To the person moving the table, I leave it to you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
FWMCも食べ終わった？
Did FWMC finish eating too?
おいしいよ！
It's delicious!
全部食べたじゃないかな？
I think we ate everything?
すごい美味しかった！
It was super delicious!
お腹いっぱい！
I'm so full!
ロールキャベツも美味しかった！
The cabbage rolls were tasty too!
美味しかった！
It was delicious!
ポトフかえりました。
The pot-au-feu is gone.
よかった。
I'm glad.
待って、クッキーが美味しすぎる。
Wait, these cookies are too delicious.
そうだよ！胃がね...
I know! The stomach...
すごい！手作りクッキーです！
Amazing! They're handmade cookies!
恐縮です。
I'm humbled.
朝から頑張らせていただきました。
I've been working hard since morning.
さすが！
As expected!
小豆が寝てる間にこねました。
I kneaded it while Azuki was sleeping.
作ってくれてます。
She made them for us.
クッキーの匂いで小豆が起きました。
The smell of cookies woke Azuki up.
最高のシェアハウス！
The best share house!
目覚めや。
What a way to wake up.
FUWAMOCOは、えっと、EXPOのござるクッキーまだあります。
FUWAMOCO, um, still has the Gozaru cookies from the EXPO.
まだあるの！？
You still have them!?
え、それ大丈夫！？
Eh, is that safe!?
食べて！
Eat them!
絶対ヤバいって！
That's definitely dangerous!
だからちょっと横に、ござるクッキーもEXPOのござるクッキーも、
So right next to it, the Gozaru cookie and the Expo Gozaru cookie...
飾ってないですか？
Are you displaying them?
フリーズドライかなんか...？
Are they freeze-dried or something...?
腐っちゃうよ！
They'll rot!
賞味期限！
Expiration date!
そんなや、賞味期限...
No way, the expiration date...
食べてあかんやつ。
You shouldn't eat those.
クッキーってだってバターとか入ってるからさ。
Because cookies have butter and stuff in them.
卵とか。
And eggs.
去年のやつ...
From last year...
あめちゃんのクッキー。
Candy cookies.
観賞用なんですよね。
It's for display, right?
そうです。
That's right.
大事なクッキーね！
Important cookies, huh!
ファンすぎるやろ。
You're too much of a fan.
手元に残しておきたい。
I want to keep them close.
ござるのクッキー、あれね、いつでも言われたら作るから。
I'll make those Gozaru cookies whenever you ask.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
永久保存版。
Permanent preservation edition.
持って帰りたいものがあれば、唐揚げとか詰めて大丈夫。
If there's anything you want to take home, packing karaage is fine.
お弁当？
Bento?
唐揚げ詰めて...
Pack the karaage...
お弁当箱みたいなやつ...
Like a bento box thing...
これね、これね。
This one, this one.
まつり先輩が持って帰るって言ってたから。
Matsuri-senpai said she'd take some home.
僕はこれだけで。
I'm good with just this.
ありがとうござ。
Thank you goza-
おにぎりだけ。
Just the rice ball.
おにぎり実は予定になかったんで。
Actually, the rice balls weren't planned.
小豆が「ガスが多いからご飯も欲しいかな」って言うから。
Because Azuki said, 'There's a lot of gas (fried food?), so maybe we want rice too.'
本当に… 来て申し訳なすぎる。
I feel so sorry for just coming here truly...
可愛いから。
Because you're cute.
まだ仕事あります。
I still have work to do.
えー！？
Ehh!?
大丈夫でしょ？
It'll be fine, right?
すいません！
I'm sorry!
頑張って。
Do your best.
常連のおじさんが、ちょっと失礼します。
The regular old man customer is excusing himself a bit.
いやみんな待ってくれて… わざわざ時間割いてくれて…
Everyone waited... and took the time out for this...
元気をチャージしてもらって。
Please recharge your energy.
いただきまーす。
Let's eat!
あ、何？ 自撮りしてる？
Ah, what? Are you taking a selfie?
自撮り…？ 自撮りだ！
Selfie...? It's a selfie!
イエーイ！
Yay!
可愛いー！
So cute!
僕も撮ろう。
I'll take one too.
本当に可愛いから。
Because you're really cute.
みんな自撮りして…
Everyone's taking selfies...
自撮りだと思ったら違った。
I thought it was a selfie, but it wasn't.
自撮りだわ。
It is a selfie.
ロールキャベツ。
Rolled Cabbage.
美味しい！
Delicious!
本当はロールキャベツ苦手やったんですよ。
Actually, I used to be bad with Rolled Cabbage.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
でも食べたら美味しくて、食べられるようになったかも。
But after eating this, it's tasty, so I might be able to eat it now.
すごい！
Amazing!
美味しい！
It's delicious!
食べれると美味しい。
It's delicious once you can eat it.
おでんのやっぱ出汁も効いて…
The oden soup stock is really effective too...
美味しくなってる。
It makes it tasty.
美味しすぎる。
Too delicious.
ホロホロ。
It's so soft and crumbly.
ホロホロになってます。
It's become so tender.
いや、それ嬉しすぎるな。
Man, that makes me too happy.
美味しすぎた。
It was too delicious.
おじ？
Old man?
おじ出た。
The old man came out.
仕事頑張って！
Good luck with work!
頑張りまーす！
I'll do my best!
頑張ってー。
Good luck.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
忙しい。
So busy.
かもしれん。
Might be.
朝からラジオの食べ物しか食べてない。
Since morning, I've only eaten the food from the radio show.
あら！
Oh my!
お腹ペコペコ？
Are you starving?
え、なんかなくない？
Eh, isn't it running out?
なくなった！
It's gone!
食べてる。
They're eating it.
色々。
Various things.
あ、大丈夫。
Ah, it's okay.
あげないからね。
I won't give it to you.
大事に… 大事に持って帰る。
I'll carefully... carefully take it home.
持って帰ってくれる？
You'll take it home?
大事に持って帰るだよ。
I'm taking it home with care!
クッキーも持って帰る。
I'll take the cookie home too.
あ、持って帰る！
Ah, taking it home!
逆でもいいかも。これだけ残して、私がこれ持って帰る。
Maybe the reverse works. Leave only this, and I take this home.
逆でもいいよ、やばい。
Reverse is fine too, oh my.
家のもので。
As a household item.
スタッフがなくなりそう。
The staff might run out of food.
それはほどほどに食べて貰ってね。
Well, have them eat it in moderation.
じゃあ助かりますか。
Then that helps.
やっぱ米とかね、粉もなくなるとあれなんで。
After all, if the rice and flour run out, it's a problem.
そうだよ。
That's right.
美味しいのいっぱい作ってきた甲斐があります。
It was worth making so much delicious food.
おにぎり貰っていいですか？
Can I have a rice ball?
いいよ！
Sure!
ご飯欲しくて…
I want rice...
今食べたい？
Do you want to eat now?
え、今食べたい。
Eh, I want to eat now.
あ、ほんと？ チンとかする？
Oh, really? Should I microwave it?
え、だったらチンしてくれて…
Eh, if you could microwave it...
おにぎり…
Onigiri...
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
梅干しすごい美味しかった！
The pickled plum was super delicious!
食べる！
I'll eat it!
梅干し？
Pickled plum?
あ、ドキドキ…
Ah, heart pounding...
御座候。
Gozasorou.
あーん。
Aahn.
想像しちゃうよ。
I'm imagining it.
やるな。
You're good.
食レポが。
The food report is...
ちなみに、米と海苔はスポンサーは風真…
By the way, the sponsor for the rice and seaweed is Kazama...
そうそうそう、風真家の…
Right right, the Kazama family's...
から届いたね。
It arrived from there.
え、そうなの！？
Eh, really!?
近所さん諸々から頂いた。
Received from the neighbors and various people.
えー！ 豪華！ 頂きます！
Ehh! Luxury! Let's eat!
海苔も含め。
Including the seaweed.
ノリノリ。
High spirits (Nori-nori).
梅干し、辿り着いた？
Did you reach the pickled plum?
んんー！ めっちゃ梅干し！
Mmmm! Very much pickled plum!
めっちゃ梅干し。
Very much pickled plum.
かなりちゃんと酸っぱみがある。
It has quite a proper sourness.
結構おにぎりとかお粥用だね。
It's quite suited for rice balls or porridge.
紫蘇もちゃんと効いてて。
The shiso flavor is working well too.
良かった！ ご飯進む系です。
I'm glad! It's the type that makes you eat more rice.
よく分かりますね、グルメな味が。
You understand it well, the gourmet taste.
酸っぱいの好きやから、丁度いい酸っぱさ。
I like sour things, so it's just the right sourness.
美味しい！
Delicious!
私も食べようかな。
Maybe I'll eat some too.
ゼータ先輩。
Zeta-senpai.
酸っぱい梅干し。
Sour pickled plum.
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
初梅干し、今食べる？
First time eating pickled plum, eating it now?
初めて食べる梅干し、ずっと記憶に残るよ。
The first pickled plum you eat will stay in your memory forever.
最初の味になるから、ずっと記憶に残る。
It becomes the baseline taste, so it stays in your memory.
酸っぱい！
Sour!
顔してる。
Making a face.
おにぎり吸ってる！
Sucking on the rice ball!
大丈夫？ 梅干しいけなかった？
You okay? Couldn't handle the plum?
お米と…
With the rice...
あ、米とね。
Ah, with the rice.
どうですか？
How is it?
酸っぱい！
Sour!
酸っぱい？
Sour?
でも、美味い。
But, it's tasty.
良かったー。
Good to hear.
あの、里の人間も喜びます。
Um, the people of my village will be happy too.
お米と海苔。
Rice and seaweed.
お米と海苔とね。
With the rice and seaweed.
うちのスポンサーの方々が喜びます。
Our sponsors will be delighted.
美味しい！
Delicious!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちなみに私、紫蘇もダメだったんだけど…
By the way, I was no good with shiso either...
えっ？
Eh?
美味しい、これ。
This is delicious.
良かった！ 今日だけで苦手克服していく。
I'm glad! Overcoming dislikes in just one day.
美味しい
It's delicious.
なんかおにぎり久しぶりに食べました、手作りの。
It's been a while since I ate a handmade rice ball.
確かに。
True.
うーん、温かさを感じる。
Mmm, I can feel the warmth.
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
ここの発端は本当は今日来たかったスバル先輩が…
The origin of this place is actually Subaru-senpai, who wanted to come today...
昔、昔でもないな、数ヶ月前か、
A long time ago... well, not that long, maybe a few months ago,
なんか、死にそうになってた時に、
when she was about to die [from exhaustion],
ご飯とおにぎりを持ってた時に、
and I had some rice and onigiri with me,
千と千尋のハクのおにぎりみたいに「うめぇ」ってなって、
she was like Haku eating the onigiri in Spirited Away, going "It's so good!"
泣きながら。
while crying.
ボロボロボロみたいな。
Just tears pouring down.
そう、スバル先輩がじゃあ今日来るんだったら、持っていくからねって、
Right, so I said if Subaru-senpai is coming today, I'll bring some for her,
言ってね、ここ始まったんだよね。
and that's how this whole thing started.
届けに行きますからねスバル先輩、呼んでくださいね。
I'll go deliver it to you, Subaru-senpai! Please call me!
ちょっとこれ無くなっちゃった。
This one is already gone...
そう、そんなことも思いながら、色々作るね。
Yeah, so I made various kinds while thinking about that.
分かるわ、その泣き出すスバル先輩の気持ちが。
I understand that feeling of Subaru-senpai bursting into tears.
愛を感じたんです。
She felt the love.
おにぎり…
Onigiri...
あったかいよ。
It's warm.
美味しい？
Is it good?
美味しい。よく揚げた。
Delicious. It's fried well.
なかなか作ることないから。
We don't really get to make them often.
作らないですね。
Yeah, we don't make them.
形で、なんか全部詰めて、形でポンってやって…
Using a mold... you stuff it all in and go 'pon' with the shape...
あるあるある。
Yeah, that exists.
そう、だけどなんか上手く出来てない気がして。
Yeah, but I feel like I can't do it well.
崩れちゃうから。
It crumbles apart.
なるほどね。え、ござるんちのおにぎりの作り方特殊だから、今度教える。
I see. Well, the way we make onigiri at my house is unique, I'll teach you.
そう、特殊だった。
Yeah, it was unique.
教わったんですけど。
I was taught how to do it.
ござるんちはかなり特殊なおにぎりの作り方を…
The Gozaru household has a pretty unique way of making onigiri...
え、気になる。
Eh, I'm curious.
ラップバーッて敷いて、
You lay out plastic wrap 'bam',
3個ぐらい海苔間隔で敷いて、
lay out about 3 sheets of nori spaced apart,
上にご飯乗っけて、
put rice on top,
ラップこう間こうパーッて切っていい感じに。
and cut the wrap in the gaps 'pam' nicely.
効率的やすい！
It's efficient and easy!
包んで、俵にしてから台形にして終わり。
Wrap it, make it into a bale shape, then a trapezoid, and done.
俵型の…
A bale-shaped...
おにぎりでした。
rice ball.
じゃあちょっとこれ実物1個おにぎり取ってもらっていいですか？
Can you pick up one of the actual rice balls here?
それ見せて。
Show that one.
うん、そういうこと？
Yeah, is that what you mean?
あ、そうそう、一回ここに、ここに出すんで。
Ah, yes, I'll put it out here for a sec.
取られるかと思った。
I thought it was going to be taken.
ちょっとあの、普通に皆さんすいません、あのよくある…お弁当おにぎりみたいなので申し訳ないんですけど。
Everyone sorry, it looks like a common... lunchbox onigiri, so I apologize.
お弁当おにぎりね。
Lunchbox onigiri, right.
うちは台形になりがちです。
Ours tends to become trapezoid-shaped.
天むすとか刺す時上からグサッといきます、こっから。
When making Tenmusu, I stab the shrimp from the top 'Gusa!', right here.
おー。
Ooh.
天むす作れるの！？
You can make Tenmusu!?
天むすは作れますよ。
I can make Tenmusu.
わ、天むすいいね。
Wow, Tenmusu is nice.
作って欲しい。
I want you to make it.
え、でも天むすにはうるさいよ、愛知。
Eh, but Aichi is picky about Tenmusu you know.
そうだよ愛知だから。
Yeah, because it's Aichi.
じゃあうちのスポンサーの方々にちょっとまた材料提供して。
Then I'll ask our sponsors to provide ingredients again.
海老、海老の提供。
Shrimp, provide shrimp.
海老のなんとかなりませんかね。
Can we manage to get some shrimp somehow?
海老いいね。
Shrimp is good.
楽しみだな。
I'm looking forward to it.
海老今日、ちょっと仕入れないといけないですね。
I need to stock up on shrimp today.
やった。
Yay.
そん時また、あの、来てください。
At that time, um, please come again.
来ます。常連になるから。
We'll come. We'll become regulars.
常連嬉しい。ありがとう。
I'm happy to have regulars. Thank you.
いや本当にありがとうございます。
No really, thank you very much.
なんかね、来てくれるからね。
Because you guys come visit us.
すいません何も持ってきてない、胃袋だけ持ってきました。
Sorry we didn't bring anything, we only brought our stomachs.
いや胃袋どうやって置いてくるんだよって。
Well, how would you even leave your stomach behind?
もっとあげてよ。
Give us more.
胃袋しかない。
We only have stomachs.
胃袋はどうやって持ってくるって来るの。
How do you 'bring' a stomach anyway?
次回は何がいいですかね？
What would be good for next time?
フワちゃんとかモコちゃん食べたいものありますか？
Do Fuwa-chan and Moco-chan have anything they want to eat?
えー、何でも好きだけど。
Eh, I like everything though.
フワちゃん先輩何が好きですか？
Fuwawa-chan senpai, what do you like?
えー、何だろうね。
Ehh, what would it be...
作って欲しい。
I want you to make it.
え、でもこうやってみんなで食べれるのがいいですもんね。
But it's nice to be able to eat together like this.
シェアできる。
We can share.
なかなかない。
It's rare.
関西で言うと…たこ焼きとか。
Speaking of Kansai... maybe Takoyaki.
ちょっと火が使えないから、難しいかな。
We can't use fire here, so that might be difficult.
ホットプレートもダメなん？
Is a hot plate no good either?
湯気が出ちゃうと…
If steam comes out...
もう作ってあるやつをみんなで囲うとか。
We can just gather around the ones already made.
で、なんかちょっとロシアンルーレットでなんかチョコ入れたりとか。
And like, play Russian Roulette by putting chocolate in some.
なんかワサビとか。
Or like Wasabi.
100個ぐらい並べてね。
Lining up about 100 of them.
クレープとか？
How about crepes?
ああ！
Ah!
アドベントでクレープ配信やってたけど、
We did a crepe stream in Advent,
なんか納豆のも入ってて。
but like, there was natto in it too.
納豆！？
Natto!?
納豆クレープ…
Natto crepe...
甘いのも入ってて、納豆も入ってて、
It had sweet things, and it had natto,
納豆も入ってて、なんか難しかった。
Natto was in it, so it was kind of difficult.
トラウマだったか。
So it was a trauma.
トラウマになってる。
It's become a trauma.
みんな可愛いクレープ作ってね。
Everyone make cute crepes, okay?
クレープもいいですね。
Crepes sound good too.
梅干しクレープとか。
Like pickled plum crepes.
すっぱいんだ。
It's sour!
クレープ。
Crepes.
まつり先輩はほら、全部吸ってね…
Matsuri-senpai, you know, sucks everything up...
全部食べたい！
I want to eat everything!
何でも来るよ。
She'll eat anything.
ワッフル！ワッフルね。
Waffles! Waffles, huh.
お二人の得意料理って何なんですか？
What are your specialty dishes?
え、何？ 得意料理？
Eh, what? Specialty dishes?
まんべんなく何でも割と作るけど…
We make pretty much anything evenly, but...
かっこいい！
So cool!
でござる、ぶっちゃけ料理よりお菓子…
I honestly prefer sweets over cooking meals...
あ、お菓子か！
Ah, sweets!
料理も、卵系かな。
For cooking, maybe egg dishes.
卵系？ だし巻きとか。
Egg dishes? Like rolled omelets.
オムライスとか。
Like Omurice.
オムライス食べたい！
I want to eat Omurice!
オムライスいいね！
Omurice is good!
オムライス結構好きなメンバー…
There are members who really like Omurice...
あ、ラプラスがね。
Ah, Laplus does.
うちは…キッズ飼ってるから。
I'm raising a kid here, after all.
やっぱキッズがオムライス食べたいって定期的に連絡くるんで。
The kid contacts me regularly saying she wants to eat Omurice.
食堂なんで、やっぱ和食の大皿の結構メニューとかをいっぱい置いて、みんなにバイキングで…
Since it's a diner, I want to put out big platters of Japanese food and have everyone eat buffet-style...
わぁ、最高！
Wow, that's the best!
仕込みの時間が大変なことになるけど…
The prep time is going to be crazy though...
それやりたい！
I want to do that!
いっぱい作ってあって、みんなこう自分で取っていくあれ。
Making a lot of food and everyone picks what they want themselves.
主菜と副菜、こう三菜…
Main dish, side dishes, like three dishes...
お金取ったほうがいいよ！
You should charge money!
本業にしたほうがいいぐらいレベルが…
The level is high enough to make it a full-time job...
お金取ったほうがいいよ！
You should definitely charge money!
払いますよみんな！
Everyone will pay!
そんなことありません。
No, no, nothing like that.
みんなが美味しく食べてくれるので…
Everyone enjoys eating it, so...
材料費がありますから！
There are material costs though!
我々もありますから。
We have them too.
デザート係なんで。
We're on dessert duty.
やりましょうまた、是非。
Let's do it again, definitely.
じゃあ、アンケートとるか。
So, shall we take a survey?
食べたいおかず、二つぐらい…
About two side dishes they want to eat...
ランキング戦にして。
Make it a ranking battle.
生で発表して、今回人気だったおかず…
Announce it live, like "The popular dish this time was..."
いや確かに。あと、料理作りたいっていう…
True. Also, people who want to cook...
作りましょう、一緒に。
Let's cook together.
何でも作りたいです！
We want to cook anything!
「何でも」って言ったな？
You said "anything," right?
よし、揚げたドーナツ作るぞ！
Alright, let's make fried donuts!
危ないけど！
It's dangerous though!
買ったほうがいいと思いますよ！
I think it's better to buy them!
なんと、もうここで…
Actually, right here...
そろそろ閉店のお時間！
It's about time to close up!
えー！
Eeeh!
フワモコさん方、全然ゆっくり食べていただいて。
FuwaMoco-san, please take your time eating.
今日はあずいろ食堂、開店ということでね。
Today was the opening of Azuiro Diner.
いっぱいフラスタもいただいたり。
We received so many flower stands.
フラスタ本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for the flowers!
みんな沢山来ていただきました、ありがとうございました。
Thank you all for coming in such large numbers.
フワモコちゃんも！
FuwaMoco-chan too!
おきゅー！
Okyu-!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
ちょっと今日は来たかったけど来れなかったよっていうホロメンからの…
There were messages from Holomems who wanted to come but couldn't today...
メッセージとかもいろいろ頂いてて。
We received various messages from them.
また次回ね、どこかでやれたらいいなと思ってます。
I hope we can do this again somewhere next time.
ホロメンが胃袋を持って食べに来てくれる限り続きます、この店。
This shop will continue as long as Holomems bring their appetites!
やったー！
Yay!
絶対行きます！
We'll definitely come!
絶対来る！
Absolutely!
バウバウ！
Bau Bau!
みんなもおでん食べて体暖めてくれよな。
Everyone, eat some oden and warm up your bodies.
最後はみんなでごちそうさまでしたで。
Let's end by saying "Gochisousama deshita" together.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
せーの！
Ready!
ごちそうさまでした！
Thank you for the meal!
美味しかったー！
It was delicious!
Please subscribe AZKi Channel
Follow me @AZKi_VDiVA